快啊
Come on.
问题在于我们经济成长趋缓
The problem is our economy is slowing down.
大家都很清楚
You all know that as well as anybody does.
也许你或你的朋友都明白
Maybe you or your friends understand
什么是信用卡借款
what it means to have credit card debt.
再加上每月的高额电费 有些人已开始觉得日子不好过
Double that with high energy bills there's some people beginning to feel pinched.
约翰?
John?
怎么了?
Honey, what's wrong?
-你们在干嘛?  -你说呢?
-What the hell are you doing? -What's it look like?
-等等  那是我的车 -银行不是这么说的
-That's my car. -That's not what the bank says.
那是我的车  拜托
That's my car! Come on!
赶快缴钱吧
Try paying your bills.
怎么回事啊?
What's going on?
对不起  银行说过会配合我的
I'm sorry.The bank promised they'd work with me.
那是两个月前的事了
John, that was two months ago.
但我们只剩一笔钱缴房租了...
I know, but I figured we're down to one last month's rent...
不是车子就是房子  我想...
it's either the car or the house, so I thought...
-你想 -你要我怎么做?
-You thought. -What do you want me to do, baby?
你想露宿街头吗?  我工时被减...
You want to be on the street? I'm down to 20 hours at the plant...
工厂都移到墨西哥  你要我怎样
they're shipping all the jobs to Mexico. What do you want me to do?
我的车没了
John, my car is gone!
我知道  我正在设法找兼差
I understand that.I'm trying to find a second job, baby, come on.
你要我说什么?  没关系吗?
You want me to say it's fine?
好  没关系
All right, it's fine!
车子还是我们的
And the car is still ours. We own it.
只等下一笔钱进来 等两周就行了
I just got to wait for my next check to come in.In two weeks we'll be fine.
麦可
Mikey?
柯罗尼  奥林匹亚先生 连续两年
Ronnie Coleman, Mr. Olympia, two years running!
好耶
Yeah!
-坐下  小乖  吃早餐 -我在吃啊
-Sit down, honey. Eat some breakfast. -I am eating.
-甜甜圈不算早餐 -这是大陆式早餐
-A doughnut isn't breakfast. -It's a continental breakfast.
我们现在不在大陆上
We're not on a continent right now.
那北美洲算什么?
Dad, what do you call North America?
不吃早餐就别上学  快吃
Enough.Now you're not going to school till you eat some breakfast, so eat.
两个都一样
Both of you.
那些混蛋竟敢拖走我们的车
I can't believe those jerks took our car.
-妈  你相信吗? -无法置信
-Can you, Mom? -No, I can't.
我们该怎么办?
What are we going to do?
你会想办法的  对吧  爸?
You're going to do something, right, Dad?
知道我会怎么做吗?
You know what I'd do?
我会发狂发狠
I'd get so big and mad,
把那些人海扁一顿
I'd just go crazy and kick someone's butt.
-别乱说话 -好
-Watch your language. -I would.
你看太多摔角比赛了
You've been watching too much of that W.W. Wrestling?
不是摔角  是健美
Not wrestling, Dad, bodybuilding.
差别很大的
There's a big difference.
去拿书  你上学要迟到了
Go get your books. You're going to be late for school.
麦克  喝
Mike, pow!
快点  小乖
Hurry up, baby.
能送我去上班吗?
Can I get a ride to work?
我爱你
I love you.
好  有了
All right, I got a good one.
-要是我有个女孩... -说吧
-If I ever seen a girl, that you... -Go ahead.
是你所爱
That you needed.
说啊  说啊
Go ahead, go ahead, go ahead.
-点苔 -海苔
-Ridshin. -Radishes.
不  是点苔
No, it's ridshin.
点状青苔
Reddish stick.
是电台
It's radio station.
电台  好吧
Radio station, okay.
很好  你赢了
It's a good one, you got me.
打卤
Hontinin.
打卤?
Hontinin?
打卤
Hontinin.
大卤面?
Hundred dollars?
不  我们早上还提过这个
No, we talked about it this morning. Hontinin.
-打卤?  -大陆
-Honiny? -Continent.
我赢了  对吧?  妈咪?
I got you, right? Mom?
你呢  妈咪?
How about you, Mom?
不要
No. No.
来玩嘛
Come on, baby.
不  你们会笑我
No. You'll just laugh at me.
来嘛  妈咪 就说车里的东西好了
Come on. Come on, Mommy. How about something in the car.
-我们不会笑你的 -我们不会笑的
-We won't laugh at you.  Come on. -We won't laugh.
拜托嘛
Please?
好吧  你不能说出正确答案
All right. But we can't know what you're saying.
你要让我们听不懂
Say it so we don't know. You got to.
仪表板
Dashboard.
什么?
What?
你说什么?
What'd you say?
我说...
I said...
仪表板  猜吧...
dashboard. Now...
什么?
What?
拜托  快来人把这女人带走吧
Hello? Come get this woman, please?
怎么  不好吗?
What, it's no good?
不要这样嘛  宝贝
Come on. Come on, baby.
我跟你玩拇指摔角
I'll thumb-wrestle you.
好
All right.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
-你赢了 -一  二  三  她赢了
-You got me. -One, two, three, she wins.
我是无敌皇后
I am the gueen.
我想到了
All right, I got one.
我也是  你该上学了
I got one for you. You're going to school.
记得带午餐
Get your lunch.
爸?
Hey, Dad?
我用零用钱存了46元
I got $46 I saved from my allowance.
你若需要可以拿去用
You can have it if you want.
我们是一家人  应该要团结
We're a family.We got to stick together, right?
没错
That's right.
但那是你的钱  好好留着吧
But you earned that money so you keep it, okay?
好  回头见了
All right. See you later.
-再见  麦克 -不是再见  我讨厌再见
-Goodbye, Mike. -Not goodbye, I hate goodbye.
记得吧?  是回头见
Remember? See you later.
好  回头见
All right, see you later.
麦克?
Mike?
菲力惠勒  275磅
Flex Wheeler, 275 pounds.
体脂肪2%
Two percent body fat.
好耶
Yeah, baby!
约翰
John!
你拿了我的砂轮?
Take my frigging grinding wheel?
什么?
What?
你拿了我的砂轮?
You take my grinding wheel?
是啊  没错
I do, don't I?
真的?
You do?
是啊  乱性感的
Yeah, have sex appeal.
不  它不见了  我的砂轮
No, it's not in my locker, my grinding wheel.
你要我的吗?
Do you want mine?
只有两个人知道我柜子的密码
Now, only two people know the combination to my locker, John.
那是我的砂轮  你很清楚
That's my grinder and you know it.
约翰  我去抽烟
John! John! Smoke, all right?
干嘛打领带?  有人死了?
What's with the frigging tie? Somebody die?
喜欢吗?
You like that?
若我今天没法子得到这工作
That's the tie I'll be wearing to my funeral
我死的时候就打这条领带
if I don't get this job today.
什么工作?  没工作的
What job? There're no jobs.
报上登的  他们在征人
I saw it in the classifieds, they're hiring.
别傻了
Forget about it.
我非去不可
I got to go, though.
为什么?
Yeah, how come?
狄妮会杀了我  她的车被吊了
Denise will kill me. They repod her car this morning.
天啊
Oh, boy.
要我陪你去吗?
You want me to go with you?
走吧
Come on.
我的钱  50分耶
Fifty cents! Fifty cents!
这是浪费时间
This is a frigging waste of time.
四百人应征一个工作  拜托
Four hundred people for one job? One job? Give me a break.
一定早内定用谁的儿子  亲戚了
Guarantee somebody's son, cousin, uncle already got this job sewn up.
他们若不想雇人  干嘛登报?
Why'd they put it in the paper if they're not hiring, Jimmy?
那只是幌子
It's the frigging runaround.
他们会说: 会将你的资料建档...
You mark my words,it's either: "We'll keep your application on file..."
不然就会说: 你超过标准
or they'll tell you: "You're overqualified."
不管怎样  他们不会用你
Either way, they'll screw you.
亚契先生?
Archibald
是的
Yes
约翰?
John
我在重工业做了15年
I have been working heavy machine for 15 years.
我需要这工作  我什么都能做
I really want the job. Everything you want I can do.
我了解
I see
若有必要  我可以今天就上工
I can start today if you, you know, you need.
你的履历令人印象深刻
Well, your resume is very impressive.
你的确很有经验
You certainly got the experience.
老实说  你也许超过标准
Frankly, you may be overqualified.
但我们会把你的资料建档
But, we'll keep your application on file.
耶稣爱我  我知道
Jesus loves me this I know.
圣经如此告诉我...
For the Bible tells me so...
爸?
Dad?
再15分就要比赛了  我们会迟到
The game starts in 15 minutes. We're going to be late.
他们孱弱  但他强壮
They are weak but he is strong.
是的  耶稣爱我
Yes, Jesus loves me!
圣经如此告诉我
The Bible tells me so
红不让  宝贝  红不让
Knock it out, baby, knock it out!
加油  汤米
Come on, Tommy!
四坏球
Ball four!
加油  麦克  加油
Let's go, Mikey!
加油  儿子
Let's go, baby! Let's go, son!
红不让  红不让
Knock it out! Knock it out!
压低头盯住球  儿子
Keep your head down on the ball, son. Head down on the ball.
为妈咪挥大棒吧  加油  麦克
Knock it out for your mama, baby! Come on, Mikey!
加油  麦克
Come on, Mikey!
好球
Strike!
别担心  儿子
Don't worry about it, son.
你瞎了啊
What're you blind?
压低头盯住球
Keep your head down on the ball!
这投手真讨厌  他几岁?
He's supposed pitcher. How old is he?
应该快12岁了 12岁个头  看看他
Twelve, my ass. Look at him.
他连胡子都长出来了
His beard grew an inch between pitches.
加油  麦克
Let's go, Mikey!
为妈咪加把劲
For your mama, baby!
手肘抬起来  儿子
Put your elbow up, son! Elbow up!
安全上垒
Safe.
跑者得点
Tie goes to the runner.
快跑  快跑
Run! Run! Run! Run!
二垒
Second base!
麦克
Mike!
怎么回事?
What happened?
天啊
Jesus.
快叫救护车
Somebody call an ambulance!
快叫救护车啊
Somebody call a frigging ambulance!
吉米  他不会有事吧?
All right, Jimmy. Is he going to be okay?
求求你  麦克  快开车
Come on, Mikey! Go!
救命啊
Help us!
救命  快来人啊
Help! Help, please, somebody!
他没法呼吸  他没呼吸了
He can't breathe, he's not breathing!
好  跟我来
All right, come with me.
他在跑向二垒的时候昏倒了
He was running to second base. He fell over.
我需要医师支援
I need a doctor right away please!
天啊
Oh, Jesus!
麦克
Mikey.
怎么回事?
What happened?
他在打棒球时昏倒
He crashed playing baseball.
给他氧气
Get him on some oxygen.
他不会有事吧?
He's going to be all right, isn't he?
醒醒  我是你妈
Wake up. Here's your mama.
以前发生过吗?
This ever happen before?
没有
No, ma'am.
他有过敏吗?
Any allergies?
没  都没有
No, nothing!
过去有没有吃药?
No medications the past year?
没有
Nothing!
对药物过敏?
Allergies to medication?
没有  他很好
No, he's fine!
他只是昏倒
He just fell down.
他的肝肿大  把他翻过去
His liver's enlarged. Flip him, please.
他不会有事吧?
He's going to be all right, isn't ge?!
脉搏150
Pulse is 150.
血氧78%  血压68/34
Pulse ox, 78 percent, B.P.68 over 34.
他到底怎么了?
What is the matter with him?!
请跟我来好吗?
Would you come with me, please?
你们有些手续要办
There are a few procedures we need to go over.
什么手续?
What kind of procedures?
我们要让他入院
We'll be admitting your son.
你们得填一些表格
You need to fill out the proper forms.
什么表格?
What kind of forms?
你儿子可能需要输血
Your son may need a blood transfusion.
什么?
What?
我们要帮你们验血  好吗?
We need to test you both for blood type, okay?
麦克  我们马上回来  小乖
Mikey, we're coming right back, baby!
等等
Wait a minute!
名字  亚契先生?
First name, Mr. Archibald?
约翰
John.
中间名呢?
Middle initial?
昆西
Quincy.
保险公司名称?
Name of your insurance company?
他人呢?  他还好吧?
Where is he? Is he okay?
还不知道  我们在等检验结果
We don't know yet. They're running tests. We're waiting for the results.
我们能帮得上忙吗?
Is there anything we can do?
你的卡  亚契先生
Your card, Mr. Archibald.
麦可的帽子
Mikey's hat.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你的保险卡
Your insurance card.
我要影印建档
I need to make a copy for our files.
没关系  你们可以进去了
It's okay, you can go in.
小乖
Hey, sweetheart.
你好吗  强棒王?
How you doing, slugger?
我不能说话
I can't talk.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
好好休息  我们等一下就走
Get your rest, buddy. We'll be cut of here in a little while.
好
Okay.
我们爱你  儿子
We love you, son.
我也爱你们
I love you too.
这些是什么?
What is all this?
这个?
This?
这监视麦克的生命征象
This monitors Mike's vitals.
呼吸率  血氧率
Respiratory rate, pulse oximetry,
心跳率
heart rate.
这个是血压
And this one is blood pressure.
舒张压和收缩压
Diastolic and systolic.
希望这数字能维持在90以上
We'd like this top number to stay above 90.
要设法不让他血压下降
If his blood pressure drops, we'll have to do something.
不能再低于70
He can't go below 70 again.
为什么?  低于70会怎样?
Why? What would that mean if he went below 70 again?
低于70  他就会心脏衰竭
Seventy and below, he's in heart failure.
好
Okay.
若有任何需要...
If you need anything...
谢谢你
Thank you.
这家人的保险情况?
How's the family insurance?
他做兼职工作
He works part-time.
她则是商店店员
She works as a grocery store clerk.
我们能怎么做?
Can we do anything?
我得挂了
I got to go.
亚契先生  太太
Mr. And Mr. S Archibald.
你们好  我是医院总监丽贝卡
Hello, I'm Rebecca Payne, hospital director.
你好
Hi.
Hi, there.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
这位是透纳医师  心脏科主任
This is Dr. Turner, the head of Cardiology
也是麦克的主治医师
and Michael's doctor.
你好
How do you do?
很好  我太太
Good. My wife.
我儿子怎样了?
How's our boy doing?
请坐
Please sit down.
好
Ok.
这张是正常9岁男孩的心脏
This x-ray shows a normal nine-year-old's heart.
这张是你儿子麦克的心脏
This x-ray is that of your son, Michael.
心房间隔有破洞...
There are septal defects...
这里  这里  和这里...
here, here, and here...
这导致心肌病变  引发肺水肿...
which have induced myopathy, resulting pulmonary edema...
以及恶性心室异位
and malignant ventricular ectopy.
所以  各位可以看到
So, you can see.
麦克的心脏比正常人要大三倍
Michael's heart is approximately three times larger than normal size.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我听不懂
I didn't understand you.
能不能说简单一点
Could you put that in layman terms for me?
基本上...
Basically...
麦克的心脏无法抽取足够血液...
There's not enough blood being pumped by Michael's heart...
所以血液会回流到肺部 逐渐堆积在里面
so it backs up in the lungs like a sponge getting wet.
他的心脏很努力  但徒劳无功
His heart is trying, but it's working too hard.
他需要什么  手术吗?
What does he need, an operation or?
他的心脏需要的不是一般手术
We're considerably beyond corrective surgery,
他的心脏毫无功用
Mike's heart is useless.
他需要心脏移植  否则就完了
He needs a transplant, or he'll die.
等等  还有别的选择
Wait a second. There are other options.
什么选择?
What options?
顺其自然  用药物治疗他
To do nothing. Medicate him.
尽量让他过的舒适一点
Make him as comfortable as possible.
仔细考虑生活品质
You'll have to think about quality of life.
我不懂
I don't understand.
他原来还好好的
We were just with him and he seemed fine.
他看起来还是会很好
He's going to seem fine.
但随着他的心脏恶化
But as his heart gets worse,
他会变得越来越累
he'll become increasingly fatigued.
他也会越睡越多
And he will sleep more and more.
有一天他会睡着...
Until one day he will fall asleep...
然后不再醒来
and he won't wake up.
我知道这很困难...
I know this is difficult...
但你们必须面对事实
but you have to face the fact
你们的儿子可能活不久
that your son may not live much longer.
你们该快乐过日子  好好道别
You might want to make it a happy time, say goodbye.
天啊
God.
心脏移植是高危险的手术
Transplantation is a high-risk operation.
你们可能在手术台上失去他
You could lose your son on that table.
你们也许并不想冒那个险
You might not want to take that chance.
要是他不做手术...
If you, you know, if he doesn't have the surgery...
不做手术  他能活多久?
If he doesn't have the surgery, how long would he live?
不会很久
Not long.
几个月  几周
Months, weeks.
几天
Days.
老天爷
God.
别哭  宝贝  不会有事的
Come on, baby. All right, all right, baby.
别哭了
Come on, now.
很抱歉...
I'm sorry, it's...
这太沉重了
It's a lot.
我会陪着你的
I'll be there.
好吧
All right.
好
Okay.
他若是你儿子  你会怎么做?
If he was your son, what would you do?
我会做移植手术  毫无疑问
I'd do the transplant, absolutely.
好吧
Okay.
好吗?
Okay?
好  就做吧  做手术
Okay, let's do that. Let's do it.
真的?
Yes?
真的
Yes.
好
Ok.
首先让麦克排上等待移植名单
First, we've got to get Mike on the organ recipient list.
他血型B型阳性  可以排第一
He's B-positive, so he should go right to the top of the list.
没这么简单
It's not so simple.
还有其他考量...
There are other considerations...
在接受移植者登上名单之前
before a prospective recipient can be placed on a donor list.
器官移植手术很花钱
Transplant surgery is very expensive.
大多都是贵的吓人
In most cases, prohibitively so.
我们有保险
We've got insurance.
我有重大疾病保险  他有纳保
I mean, I got major medical. He's covered.
我们跟你的保险公司查过
We've checked with your carrier, Mr. Archibald.
你的保险不包括这种大手术
There are no provisions in your policy for a procedure of this magnitude.
不  不你弄错了
Oh, no, no, no, no. That's a mistake.
我不是说你错了
Not that you're making the mistake.
我是说我的确有保险
I'm just saying that I'm insured.
我儿子有保险
My son's covered.
你呢  亚契太太?
How about you, Mrs. Archibald.
你有保险吗?
Do you have coverage?
不  我才刚上班几个月...
No, I've only been at the supermarket a few months, and you don't get benefits...
那不重要  我们有保险
Doesn't matter, we got insurance.
好吧  我知道你没有房产
Okay, I can see here that you don't own your home.
没有股票  债劵或投资
You've no stocks, no bonds, no investments.
你们有大约一千元的存款
You have a little over $1000 in savings.
但我们有保险
But we got insurance.
那很好  亚契先生
That may be, very well.
你去跟你的保险公司查清楚
Archibald, you'll have to check withy your carrier on that.
同时  我们只收现金
In the meantime, we'll have to treat this as a cash account.
什么?
What?
器官移植要多少钱?
How much does a transplant cost?
等等  让我...
Wait a minute, baby, let me...
要多少钱?
How much does it cost?
移植手术  医师费
Transplant surgery, doctors' fees,
术后疗养费...抗排斥药...
postoperative care...immunosuppressant drugs...
至少需要二十五万
you're looking at a minimum of $250,000.
若你们选择器官移植手术
If you opt for transplant surgery,
就要这么多
that is your choice.
但医院对于必须付现的病患
But the hospital maintains a very strict
有严格的规定
policy with regard to cash patients.
在把病患名列等待移植名单前
We require a down payment before
我们要求先付头款
we put a patient's name on a receiver's list.
那是多少?
How much?
什么样的头款?
What kind of down payment?
三成
Thirty percent.
七万五千元
Seventy-five thousand dollars.
七万五千元...
Seventy-five thousand dollars...
就为了把我儿子的名字放上去
to put my son's name on a list.
我儿子病危  你却满嘴铜臭
Our son is dying and all you can do is talk about money?
医疗是有成本的
It costs money to provide health care.
你们花钱  我们也要花钱
It's expensive for you, it's expensive for us.
很抱歉
Now, I'm sorry.
你们得保证在安排名单前付款
You'll have to guarantee payment before I can put your son's name on the list.
亚契先生  太太  请等一下
Mr. And Mrs. Archibald? Please wait!
要是你们不医  可以
If you people won't treat us, fine.
我们带他去公立医院
We'll take him to County Memorial.
相信我  别那么做
You don't want to do that.
公立医院必须救治他
It's a county hospital. They have to treat him.
他们不行
No, they don't.
心脏移植是选择性手术
Heart transplantation is considered an elective procedure.
相信我  来这里绝对没错
Believe me, you're in the right place.
那我们该怎么办?
What are we supposed to do?
再去跟你们的保险公司谈谈
You talk to your insurance company again.
找我们人力资源部请求资助
Check with our Human Resources office for medical assistance.
他们有钱
There's money.
去儿童福利局  申请医疗补助
There's Children Stats Services and there's Medicaid.
找办法让他留在这里
You find a way to keep him here.
不要接受任何人的拒绝
You don't take no for an answer.
你的保单变更过了  亚契先生
Your policy has changed, Mr. Archibald.
变更什么?
Changed to what?
我们最近更换了承保组织  从PPO改为HMO
We've recently switched carriers from a PPO to an HMO.
那比较便宜
It's less expensive
但很不幸地  他们的限制较多
but unfortunately there are some restrictions.
什么限制?
What kind of restrictions?
情况是这样的
Here's how it works.
非管理阶层  兼职员工  像你...
Non-management, part-time employees, such as yourself...
只能得到第二级的巨灾保障
only qualify for second-tier catastrophic coverage.
我是全职  不是兼职
No, I'm not part-time, I'm full-time.
是工厂生意不好
It's just slow now.
没错
Sure.
但你的保险以工时为计算基础...
But your coverage is based on hours worked...
我说过  你只能得到第二级保障...
and like I said, you only qualify for second tier...
保险给付最高是二万元
and that has a maximum payout limit of $20,000.
什么?
What?
公司每周按时扣我的款
You take money out of my check every week.
我付保险费已经付好几年了...
I've been paying into this policy for years...
没错
Right,
所以我们会全额给付二万元
and that's why we'll cover you for the full 20.
你骗我  对吧?
You're kidding me, right?
你是说你改变了我的承保条件
I mean, come on. You're telling me that you've dropped me from full-time to part-time.
你们换了承保组织
You switched carriers.
却告诉我  我保障不够?
Now you're telling me that I'm not fully covered?
就算我手上保单说我有保障?
Even though I got a policy that says I am?
这似乎不太对  对吧?
It doesn't seem right.
没错
No, it doesn't seem right.
我儿子命在旦夕
My son is very sick.
要是我没保险  问题就大了
If I'm not covered, I got a serious problem.
我明白  但我无能为力
I understand that. But there's nothing I can do.
听着  你可以上诉
You can file an appeal.
是吗?
Yeah?
拿去
Here you go.
那要费时约七个工作天
That takes about seven working days.
"约翰Q(父亲)"
"总薪金(税前)$18200"
上面写你们已经有医疗保险了
Says here you already have medical insurance.
那不够
Not enough.
我们仅有的保险给付已经用尽
What little we have is already used up.
有接受政府救济吗?
You on welfare?
没有
No.
你们应该接受的
You should be on welfare.
救济?  我们都有工作啊
Welfare? We both have jobs.
那真是太糟了
That's too bad.
抱歉  我帮不上忙
I'm sorry, I can't help you.
去找郡政府要医疗补助吧
Try County Medical.
我要找承办财务补助的人员
I need to speak to somebody in financial aid.
我不想等
I don't want to hold.
我已等15分钟了  我不要等
I've been holding for 15 minutes. I don't want to hold.
我没有吼
I'm not yelling!
有  你在里面吼
Yes, you yelling in here!
下一位
Next, please.
排错了  15号窗口
Wrong line. Number 15.
什么?
What?
15号窗口...
Window 15...
不行
No.
不行什么?
No, what?
不行  你资格不符
No, you don't qualify.
我儿子病危  我破产
My son's dying, I'm broke.
要是我不够资格  谁够?
If I don't quality, who does?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你抱歉?
You're sorry?
我不需要你抱歉  我要你帮我
I don't need you to be sorry. I need you to help me?
"奈曼机械"
"您的上诉申请已获准"
不对  这是上诉
No, no, no, this is an appeal.
上诉是针对已申请的理赔案件
An appeal is for an already existing claim.
你要提出的是申诉
You needed to file a grievance.
你弄错了
You filed the wrong paperwork.
你得重提申诉  这得耗30天
Wait...You'll have to resubmit. It could take 30 days.
我没有30天可耗
I don't have 30 days.
我知道
I know.
我听够藉口了
I'm sick of the runaround.
我要让我儿子排上那个名单
What I need is my son's name on that list.
你们尚欠三万元医药费
Your account is in excess of $30,000.
医院已经尽量通融你们了
The hospital has bent over backwards to help you out.
是吗?
Is that right?
没错
Yes, it is right.
但我们的慷慨是有限度的
But, there's a limit to our generosity.
总之  你的保险没用
Once and for all, your insurance does not cover this.
拿去吧
Take it.
小心
Watch your step.
这玩意真重
This thing is frigging heavy!
别挡路
Get out of the way.
"你不能说你不要投球"
"You can't say that you're not going to pitch."
可以了
Hey. It's okay.
我们祈祷吧
Let us pray.
慈爱的天父派遣其子耶稣...
God of mercy into whose hands your son, Jesus Christ...
在死前交付了他的灵魂
commended his spirit at his last hour.
在它手中
Into those same hand,
我们颂扬您的仆人蒂凡尼
we commend your servant Tiffany.
你该去找那个记者
You should try that news guy,
他专做特别报导的
does all the special investigative reports.
那个头发超整齐的家伙
The guy with the frigging hair.
自恋狂  他叫什么来着?
Pretty boy, what's his frigging name?
姓蓝
Lampley.
蓝塔克
Tuck Lampley.
20元买电视
Give you $20 for the TV.
那是彩色电视耶
It's a color TV.
20元
Twenty dollars.
就找他吧  吉米
Call him up, Jimmy.
边走边谈  我很忙  快
Mind if we walk and talk, I'm up to here today. Go, go, go.
没关系
Not at all.
我能帮上什么忙?
So, what can I do you for?
我儿子麦克
My son, Mike.
他打棒球时心脏病发
He fell into heart failure at his little league game.
我公司本来有给我全额保险
No I got full insurance from the job.
但他们现在却说不能付钱
Now, they're telling me they won't pay.
医院呢?  他们不能帮忙吗?
What about the hospital? Don't they have to cover it?
不  他们还叫我要付现
No, they're telling me I got to pay cash.
不然我就得眼睁睁看儿子死
Otherwise, I got to take my son home and watch him die.
老天爷
Jesus.
是啊
Yeah.
我们想也许你能做个特别报导
We were thinking you could do one of those special-interest pieces.
呼吁捐款  写信给国会议员...
Send donations, write your congressman...
只要你能帮忙  任何忙都行
Anything you can do, Mr. Lampley, would help. Anything.
你儿子的事太惨了  我想帮忙
What's happening to your son is outrageous and I want to help.
但我得照规矩来
I got to run this by my producers.
我跟大家一样都有老板
I got bosses like everybody else.
没错  没错
Right, right.
留个电话给凯伦  就在前面
Leave your number with Karen, up front?
好  谢谢你
Okay. Thank you very much. Okay.
出给我一百  一百吧
Give me $100. Give me 100.
拜托  那是钻戒耶
Come on, it's a diamond ring.
好吧  90  给我90
All right, $90. Give me 90.
（出售）
喂?
Hello?
他快死了
He's going to die.
什么?
What?
他们要叫他出院
They're releasing him.
谁?
Who?
透纳医师刚离开...
Dr. Turner just left here...
他们今早请麦克出院
and they are releasing Mike this morning.
等等  他们不会送他回家的
Baby, wait a minute. No, they won't send him home.
我昨天才交钱给他们
I gave them money yesterday.
那不重要  约翰  听我说
It doesn't matter, John, listen to me.
他们要他出院
They are releasing him.
拜托  我跟医院谈过
Come on, baby, I talked to the hospital.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
你老是说你会处理一切
You always take care of everything.
我会的
I will.
但老是处理不好  对吧?
But, it's never enough, is it?
你得想想办法
Now, you need to do something!
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
你听清楚了? 想办法
Do something!
你复原的很好
You're doing great.
真的  你大概重了五磅吧?
You really are. You've gained, what, about five pounds?
我想你是这里唯一吃得下的人
You're the only patient I have who actually eats the food in this place.
医生  请问你
Doc, let me ask you something.
我何时才能打网球?
How long before I'm able to play tennis?
别闹了  干嘛急着打球?
You couldn't play tennis before your new heart. Why would you want to play now?
改打中国结吧?
Take up knitting, okay?
我会打网球
I play tennis.
我们不在乎  甜心
We don't care, sweetheart.
回去做事吧  谢谢你
Please get back to work. Thank you so much.
海蒂  安排我们下周共进晚餐
Heidi, make an appointment for us to have dinner next week.
我来做菜
I'm going to cook.
不  千万不要
No, you're not going to cook.
你可别穿性感内衣绕着他转
And you're not wearing any lingerie around him for the next month.
他遗产没你的份  他告诉我的
Because you're not in his will, he told me.
别冒不必要的风险
So, don't push your luck.
我昨天交了六千元给医院
I gave the hospital $6000 yesterday.
我能跟你谈谈吗?
Can I talk to you?
好  没问题
Yes, sure.
很好
Okay.
好好照顾他
Okay, take care of him.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我太太说你要麦克出院  是吗?
My wife says you're sending Michael home. Is that true?
亚契先生  我只是医生
Mr. Archibald, I'm a physician.
政策不是我决定的
I don't make policy decisions.
那是由董事会决定
That's handled by the board of trustees.
你是心脏外科主任
You're the head of Cardiac Surgery.
只要你建议  他们会听
You make a recommendation, they'll listen.
我常常作建议
I make recommendations all the time.
但最后决定权在董事会 就这样  把他送回家
The final decision rests with the board, not me. That's it. Send him home.
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
我们能一起散个步吗?
Can we take a little walk?
不会太久  我保证
It won't take long, I promise you.
好
Fine.
我昨晚看医院简介
So, I'm looking at the brochure last night.
上面写说 每年做超过三百件心脏手术
It says that this hospital does over 300 heart surgeries a year.
三百件手术
Three-hundred surgeries.
每件收25万  共有多少呢?
Two-hundred fifty thousand dollars a pop. You know how much that is?
我算过了
I did the math.
心脏手术就值七千五百万...
That's 75 million dollars worth of heart surgeries...
而你却不能帮我的忙  一个忙都不帮
and you can't do one for me in good faith?
约翰  我没收你儿子诊疗费
John, I waived my fee in your son's case.
我不是要你免费
I'm not asking you to waive it.
没人要你免费看病
Nobody asked you to waive the fee.
我能筹到钱
I can raise the money.
我已筹到两万二  我付钱了
I already came up with $22,000. I paid you guys.
我向上帝发誓  我会付钱
I swear to God on my life, I'll pay for this.
只要给我个机会
Just give me the opportunity.
我工时已被减成20小时了
I'm only getting 20 hours on the job. You understand?
我做得到  我能付钱  我发誓
I can do this. I can pay, I swear to God.
我会付钱的
I'll pay you the money back.
我不知怎么付  但我发誓会付
I don't know how, but I promise I will.
你只要相信我
You just got to trust me.
我向你发誓  拜托
I give you my word as a man. Please.
请你把手拿开好吗?
Could you take your hands off me, please?
我已经尽力了  抱歉
I've done everything I can, I'm sorry.
你没有
No, you haven't.
我有
Yes.
我们进去谈吧
Let's go inside and talk about it.
我不再求人了  我告诉你
I'm not asking anymore, doctor. I'm telling you.
帮我儿子弄颗新心脏  懂吗?
You are going to give my son a new heart, you understand me?
是  我明白
Yes. Yes.
好
Okay.
别动
Don't move.
不准动
你想都别想
Don't even think about it!
把手放下
Put your hands down.
亚契先生...
Mr. Archibald...
闭嘴
Shut up.
我知道你不爽  但不能这样
I know you're upset. But this is not the way to handle it.
你们不能走这边
Hey, you can't go through this way.
把手举起来
Put your hands up!
举起来  举起来
Put them up! Put them up!
把枪给我
Give me your gun.
我没有枪
I don't have a gun.
他们没枪  他们没武装
They don't have guns.
好  好吧
All right,
把手放下  坐下
put your hands down, sit down, sit down.
不  站起来
No, no, get up.
这会给你儿子带来危险的
You fail to realize the jeopardy that you are putting your son in.
我们得谈谈...
We've got to talk...
闭嘴  别动
Shut up. Don't move.
好  快住手
Okay, just stop, stop, stop, stop!
好  快住手  你若再继续...
Okay, just stop, because if you do this...
你就走上不归路了  你懂吗?
you're in an irreversible course of action. You understand that?
踩个刹车想清楚
Put on the brakes and think about this!
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
亚契先生  我希望...
Mr. Archibald, I hope...
请你退后
Back up, please.
什么?
What?
照他说的去做
Do as he says.
请你退后
Please back up?
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
我接纳了你的建议
Taking your advice.
我不再接受任何人的拒绝了
I'm not taking no for an answer.
那个人有枪
That guy's got a gun!
你在干嘛?  你在干嘛?
What are you doing? What are you doing?
退回去  别管闲事
Get back over there! Sit on your hands over there!
过去
Get over there!
透纳  每个人  坐下
Turner, everybody! Get down!
透纳  坐下
Turner, get down!
坐在自己的手上
Sit on your hands!
把你的手放在屁股下
Put your hands under your butt!
任何人都别动
Don't anybody move!
你在干嘛?
Hey, what are you doing?
我在流血  我是来缝合手指的
I'm bleeding. Trying to get my goddamn fingers sewn back on.
亚契先生  这些人是无辜的
Mr. Archibald, these people have nothing to do with this.
你得放他们走  他们需要就医
Let them go. They need treatment.
你是医生干嘛不动手? 医他吧
This is hospital. You're doctor. Why don't you treat them? Start with him.
怎么了  医生?
What's the matter, doctor?
你要先检查他的保险卡吗?
You want to see his insurance card first?
我来
I'll do it.
好  你来
Okay, you do it.
等等  我老婆要生孩子了
I got a pregnant wife, here.
好  好  好
Okay, all right. All right, all right.
听着  等等  大家听着
Listen, wait. Listen, everybody.
好  这间医院换新老板了
All right, the hospital's under new management now.
没错
Yeah.
从现在起大家看病免费  怎样?
From now on, free health care for everybody. How's that?
好耶  老兄
Oh, righteous, man!
别一直用力压啊
Don't squeeze it like you crazy.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
麦斯
Max.
麦斯  你跟透纳医生  跟我来
Max, you and Dr. Turner, come with me.
你有那台电梯的钥匙吗?
You got keys for that elevator?
好  我要你关闭电源
Okay. I want you to kill the power.
注意看着他  麦斯
Keep an eye on him, Max.
别乱动  这样我没法子缝
Sit still. I can't do this if you're moving.
你真是青年才俊
You remind me of Doogie Howser.
我们比那个黑鬼早到的
Hey, we were here before the black guy.
每个人都会轮的到
Everybody will get their turn.
我们暂时会留在这里  忍着点
We're not going anywhere for a while, so sit tight.
听着  放轻松点  好吗?
Look, just relax, okay?
喂?
Hello?
喂  是希望纪念医院吗?
Hello, is this Hope Memorial Hospital?
对  这是希望纪念医院急诊室
Yeah, this is Hope Memorial, Emergency Room.
请问该怎么走才能到医院
Could you give me directions? I need to get there.
不行
No.
什么?
What?
不行  太太
No, ma'am.
我们闭馆维修  你得打...
We're closed for repairs. You'll have to call...
什么意思?  这很紧急的
What do you mean? This is an emergency!
我知道这很紧急
I understand that it's an emergency, ma'am.
你试过天使医院吗?
Have you tried Mount Angel?
我不知道那里怎么去?
I don't know how to get there.
平常都是我老公开车
My husband usually drives.
我需要人告诉我怎么走
I'm going to need some directions.
你从哪里来的?
Which way are you coming from?
好  往佛洛街开去  右转
Ok, Go down Flower, make a right turn.
直走到底左转  懂了吗?
Go to the end, make a left. Understand?
你要我怎么办?
What do you want me to do?
小姐  出来
Miss, get out from under there.
你要我在哪生小孩?
Where do you want me to have this baby?
出来  快出来
Come from out of there. Come on out.
去坐在那边
Go sit over there.
真不可思议  这地方真可笑
Unbelievable. This place is a joke.
还好我没受伤
Good thing I'm not cut.
不然我就死定了  对吧?
I'd bleed to death in this joint. Right, my man?
抱歉  老兄
Excuse me, brother man.
不  你得采取行动  好吗?
No, no, no. You need to do something, Steve, all right?
你得起来  做点什么
You need to get your butt up, and you need to go!
采取行动
Do something!
蜜丽  坐下
Miriam, please sit down?
我不要坐
No, I don't want to sit!
你是怎么了?
What is wrong with you?
等等  等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
别激动  孩子还没生呢
Relax. Don't have the baby yet.
何时会生?
What is it due?
随时
Any minute.
好吧  还没生
Okay, all right. Don't have it.
我要生了
I'm having it.
还没  撑着点
Not yet. Hang on.
老兄
Hey, brother.
她要生了  等一下
She's having a baby. Hang on for a second.
抱歉  老兄
Excuse me, brother man.
你等一下  这位女士要生了
Can you hang on?! The woman's having a baby!
她何时能看医生?
When is she going to see a doctor?
坐下
Sit down!
Sit down.
好吧
That 's cool, man.
克莱医生
Dr. Klein!
我马上过去
I'll be there in a minute.
你跟我没过节  你懂吧?
You and me, we got no problems. You know what I'm saying?
没错  我们没过节  坐好
That's right, we don't have a problem. Just staying in the seat.
我听不懂你在说什么
I don't understand what you're saying, ma'am.
耳朵?  耳朵感染?
The ear? Ear infection?
你能帮她医治吗?
Can you help her?
我?
Me?
就是你
You.
不行
I can't.
为什么?
Why not?
我什么都不懂  我第一天上班
I don't know anything. It's my first day.
大家都到另一个房间去
Everybody in the other room.
大家现在就去另一个房间
Everybody in the other room right now.
我们会医好你  我保证
We'll take great care of you. I promise.
保持清醒
Stay focused on me.
开门
Open up!
开门  有枪伤病患
Open up. We got a gunshot victim.
他大量失血
He's lost a lot of blood.
去别家医院
Go to another hospital.
快开门
Let's go. Open the door.
你认得这些人?
You now these guys?
认得
Yeah.
你确定?
You sure?
他们常来这里
They're here all the time.
开门
Open the door.
把你的外套脱掉
Take your jacket off.
什么?
What?
快点  快脱掉
Open it up. Take it off.
把它放地上  走开  把他留下
Just put it on the ground. Walk away. Leave him there.
留下他就对了  快走
Just leave. Go, go. Go!
快走
Just go!
他怎么了?
What's wrong with him?
他中枪了
He got shot.
好  走吧
All right, come on.
等等  这袋子里是什么
Hey, wait, I want to see what's in this bag.
你怎么了?
What happened to you, buddy?
我把收银机里的钱都给了他们
I gave them all the money in the register.
但他们还是对我开枪
They shot me anyway.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
他得立刻手术  送进外伤病房
He needs surgery now. Can I take him to Trauma one?
好
Okay.
好的
All right.
情况如何?
What do we got?
腹部枪伤
Gunshot wound to the belly.
急救人员有做任何处置吗?
Did we get anything from the EMTs?
没有
No.
透纳医生  我们需要你帮忙
Doc Turner, we'll need a hand.
天啊
Oh, man.
帮我一把吧?
Give me a hand?
三  二  一  抬起来
Three, two, one, lift.
谢谢
Thank you.
我帮不上忙  这是枪伤
No, I can't handle this. This is a gut shot.
我是心脏外科的  不是急诊科
I'm a cardiac surgeon. I'm not an Emergency Room physician.
这跟骑脚踏车一样简单
It's like riding a bike, doc.
就假装你有收费吧
Pretend you're getting paid.
这是萍果跟橘子的差别  不行
This is apples and oranges, okay?
他快死了  救救他
He's dying. Help me.
我想救他  但我没有...
I'd like to help him. I haven't done...
动手吧
Do it!
注射止痛剂  局部麻醉
Seventy-five milligrams Demerol I.V. Lidocaine, two percent local.
立刻洗手
Scrub right now.
局部麻醉免了  改全身麻醉
Forget the local. I'm putting him to sleep.
我出去后要告这家医院跟保安
When I get out of here, I'm suing this hospital and your security company.
你凭什么认为你一定能出去?
What makes you so sure you're getting out of here?
来了
Here we go.
好了  请站到线后
All right, you got to stand behind the line, sir.
把这辆车弄出去  谢谢
Move this out of here for me? Thank you.
副队长  麻烦大了
Lieutenant. We got a real problem here.
什么麻烦?
What's that?
这家伙准备长期抗战
This guy's in for the long haul.
他锁住急诊室
He's locked the E.R.,
把自己困在里面  关闭电梯电源
barricaded himself in and killed the power in the elevators.
我们若破门而入 他会大开杀戒
If we bust down the door, this son of a bitch might start killing people.
急诊室里有两架监视摄影机
There's two video cameras hidden in the E.R.
是属于医院监视系统
The hospital's surveillance.
我们正在设法连结视讯
We're setting up a video tap.
你负责保全?
You in charge of security?
不  是皮瓦利  他今天休假
No. That's Wally Pitoniak. It's his day off.
不再是了  叫他过来
Not anymore, it ain't. Get him down here.
能弄条安全的通话线路吗?
Can you get me a secure line?
行
Yes.
副队长  里面的人有无线电
Lieutenant, we got one of our guys on the inside.
你也许会想试试
He's got a walkie-talkie. You might want to try this.
切断急诊室的电话线路
Put a clamp on all pone lines to the E.R.
他若拿起电话  我要他跟我谈
If he picks up the phone, I want him talking to me.
没问题
Done.
谁是这里的负责人?
Who's in charge here?
丽贝卡
Rebecca Payne, sir.
她今天也休假
It's her day off too.
天  这医院到底有没有人上班
Does anybody work at this hospital?
今天是周六
It's Saturday, sir.
那又怎样?
So what?
周六也会有人生病  不是吗?
People get sick on Saturday, don't they?
没哭了
No cry.
亚契先生  我要帮她做内诊
Mr. Archibald, I need to do an internal exam on her.
你要带她去哪?
Where are you going to take here?
那边的诊疗室
Examination room there.
好  去吧
Good. Go.
天啊
Oh, my God.
记住  这不是你的错
Remember, it ain't your fault.
对不起
Excuse me.
我未婚妻的手可能断了
I think my fiancee might have broken her arm.
是不是有人能医治她?
Could somebody take a look at her, please?
当然  怎么回事?
Sure, what happened?
有个醉鬼闯红灯...
A drunk ran a red light...
他撞上我们
He slammed into us.
对吧?
Right?
对
Yep.
那是个意外
It was an accident.
没错
Yes, it was.
这是警察
This is the police department.
我要跟负责的人谈
I'm speaking to the man in charge.
请打开无线电
Please pick up the walkie-talkie.
这栋建筑已被团团围住
The building is surrounded.
你们已无法出入
There's no way in or out,
你若听见  我建议你接听
So if you hear me, I advise you to respond.
喂?
Hello?
喂?  有人在吗?
Hello? Is anyone there?
有
Yeah.
我是芝加哥警局的葛副队长
This is Lieutenant Frank Grimes of the Chicago Police Department.
你是负责的人?
Are you the man in charge?
没错
That's right.
请问你是?
Who am I speaking to?
约翰...
John...
老Q
Q.
好  约翰老Q
All right, John Q.
重覆  我是葛副队长
Again, I'm Lieutenant Grimes,
但我要你叫我法兰  可以吗?
But I want you to call me Frank. Can you do that?
好  法兰
Sure, Frank.
我负责人质谈判
I'll be the hostage negotiator.
我当警察35年  我都这么做
I've been a cop for 35 years. This is all I do.
我不玩花样  也不耍人
I don't play games. I don't fool around.
我说的话  你绝对可以相信
So if I say something, you can take it to the bank.
我们来谈谈吧
Now, let's get down to it.
有人受伤吗?
Is anybody hurt?
这是急诊室  大家都受了伤
It's an E. R. Everybody's hurt.
他们很好
They're fine.
很好
Good.
继续这样  我们就能好好谈
An long as it stays that way, we can keep talking.
你想要什么?
What is it that you want?
你找到丽贝卡
You find Rebecca Payne,
希望纪念医院的行政主管
Hope Memorial's administrative supervisor.
找到她
You find her.
叫她把我孩子放上移植名单
You tell her I want my kid's name on the donor's list.
听清楚了?  把我孩子放上名单
My kid's name on the donor's list.
是儿子还是女儿?
Kid boy or girl?
儿子
A boy.
我自己有两个儿子
I got two boys myself, John.
两个女儿  两个儿子
Two girls and two boys.
别想耍我  法兰  你明白吗?
Don't handle me, Frank. You understand me?
我不喜欢被耍  我没那么笨
I don't want to be handled. It insults my intelligence.
别激动  约翰  千万别激动
Take it easy, John. The idea's not to get too excited.
我想怎样就怎样  你明白吗?
I'm going to take it any way I can get it. You understand me?
这是我的要求
Now, this is what I want.
要是做不到...
If I don't get it...
你就会害死人
there'll be some dead bodies on your hands.
听明白了?
Understand me?
我听的很清楚  我会写下来
I hear you loud and clear. I'll jot that down.
丽贝卡  对吧?
Rebecca Payne. Right?
对
All right.
外面有很多警察  约翰
Now, there're a lot of cops out here, John.
你确定你要这么做?
Sure you want to go through with this?
对  我确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
好  等着吧
All right, sit tight.
你的处境很艰困  有很多问题
You're in a tough spot, John. A lot of trouble.
但你若跟我合作  讲理一点
But if you work with me, if you're reasonable,
我们总会想出解决的办法
we'll figure a way out.
我们必须对彼此有坚定信念
We have to have faith in one another.
为什么?
Why is that, Frank?
Why?
信念就是这样
That's what faith's all about.
去相信你不想相信的东西
Believing what you don't want to believe.
不管怎样  你又能怎么办?
Besides, what else are you going to do?
我要做羊膜穿刺
I want my epidural.
太迟了
Too late.
她很痛  医生...
She's in pain, doc...
出去
Out!
她不会有事的
She'll be fine.
第一胎?
First child?
对  没错...
Yeah. Yeah, I'm...
我有点紧张
I'm kind of nervous.
是啊  我以前也一样
Yeah, I was too.
你想要儿子还是女儿?
Do you want a boy or girl?
都好
It doesn't matter to me, man.
只要孩子健康就好
As long as my kid's healthy.
我只求这样
That's all I want.
听着  我说这话没有恶意
Listen, I didn't mean anything by that, man.
当时谁在开车?
Who was driving?
车子  谁在开?
The car. Who was driving?
是我
I was.
这跟那有什么关系?
What's that got to do with anything?
为什么她受伤  你却没有?
Why's your girl all banged up and you're not?
那你认为这是什么?
What do you call this?
你笑什么?
What are you laughing at?
快帮这家伙拿个OK绷吧
Somebody get this fool a Band-Aid.
我不希望你失血过多而死
I don't want you to bleed to death.
去你的  这很痛的
Screw you, man. That shit hurts.
他的安全气囊弹开  我的却没有
His air bag went off and mine didn't.
你开那一种车?
What kind of car?
奔驰500
Mercedes 500.
你开奔驰500?
You drive a Mercedes 500?
哪个年份的?
What year?
1986年的
Nineteen eighty-six.
那是经典名车
It's a classic.
奔驰的乘客座在88年以前 并没有装安全气囊
Mercedes didn't make passenger-side air bags till 1988.
逮到了
Busted.
你想说什么  约翰?
What's your point, John?
你呢  米区?
What's yours, Mitch?
重点是你竟敢痛下杀手
Point is you from the slap-a-ho tribe.
你想甩了这位小姐
You like to beat on the lady,
大家都明白
and everybody here knows it.
我当时喝醉了
I was drunk, all right?
别在这里抽烟
Don't smoke in here.
拜托  通融一下 行个方便吧
Come on, man. Give me a break. Work with me here.
我尽力了
I'm trying my best.
老Q先生  我能喝点水吗?
Mr. Q, can I get some water?
我需要上个厕所
And I need to tinkle.
我饿到胃痛了
Man, I got missed-meal cramps.
我很饿  弄一桶炸鸡进来吧
I'm hungry. Let's get a bucket of chicken in here.
马上就好  好吗?
In a minute, okay?
里面情况如何?
How's it going in there?
他死不了的
He's going to make it.
你知道这家伙失了多少血吗?
Do you have any idea how much blood this guy lost?
真不可思议  他救了这人一命
It's incredible. He saved this man's life.
那是什么?
What's that?
来西斯
Lasix.
能帮他排除多馀水份的利尿剂
It's a diuretic to help get rid of some of the fluid buildup.
但他会流失钾  所以要补充这个
But it's potassium depleting, so he needs this one to supplement.
那些呢?
And those?
度巴明是为了控制血压
Dopamine for his blood pressure.
毛地黄刺激心脏  这是医肺积水
Dig for his heart. Primacor.
天啊  真多
Gosh, it seems like so much.
是啊  这是抗生素
Yeah, it's a lot. This is antibiotic.
做什么的?
What for?
这是预防用药  以备万一
Well, it's prophylactic, just in case.
那些呢?
And those?
这两个是控制疼痛的
These two, they're for pain.
我很不舒服
I don't feel so good.
这会让你暂时觉得有点不舒服
This'll make you feel yucky for a few minutes, buddy.
但我会去拿点小冰块给你吃
But I'm going to get you some of those crunchy ice chips to chew on.
怎么样?
How's that sound?
对了  麦克
Hey, Mike, by the way,
刚刚有个人过来看你
there was this guy, he stopped by to see you.
他说他是你的朋友
Said he was a friend of your.
我把他带到这里来了
I got him right here.
我不知道该不该让他进来
I didn't know if I should let him in or not.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
他很好
Yeah, he's okay.
他说他想陪你
Said he wanted to hang out with you.
他很好
He's okay.
真好
That's great.
好了
Okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我的宝贝
My baby.
让我抱我的宝贝
Let me hold my baby!
妈...
Mom...
爸会来吧?
Is Dad coming?
会  他会来
Yeah. He's coming.
什么时候?  他在哪里?
When? Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他会来的
But he's coming.
你在做什么?
What are you up to?
别管我  没用的家伙
Never mind me. You're worthless.
烂保全  你该趁机扳倒他的
Some security guard. You should have zapped him when you had the chance.
用什么扳倒他?
Zap him with what?
何况  我才不要冒险
Besides, I'm not sticking my neck on the line.
又没钱可以捞
Not for 8.50 an hour, I'm not.
你疯了?
Are you nuts?
你到底在干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
为自己找出路
Looking out for number one.
你想活命  就坐好等人来救
Man, you want to stay alive, you sit tight and wait for the cavalry.
醒醒吧  警方一定会杀进来
Wake up. The cops are coming in shooting.
他们才不在乎他儿子
They don't care about his kid,
他明白这一点之...
and once he realizes that...
我们就玩完了
we're all history.
要是他逮到你  你才玩完了
He catches you with that scalpel, then you're the one that's history.
是吗?
Really?
没错
Yeah.
我觉得他并不可怕
He don't look so bad to me.
氯乙烷  闻起来像豆蔻
Ethyl chloride. Just like mace.
听着  把那些东西放回去...
Put the stuff back before you get us...
你才给我听着  猪头警卫
You listen to me, you stupid rent-a-cop.
我可不是笨蛋
I am not a slob.
我的人生很棒  很重要
I have a life, and it means something to me.
我才不要死在这里  绝不
I'm not going down in this shithole. No, sir.
你好  你们好
How are you? How are you doing?
你好  你好
How are you? How are you?
各位好
How are you, fellas?
暴徒是否要求让他儿子动手术?
Is it true the man inside wants an operation for this son?
你好啊
Hey, how you doing, man?
孟局长  知道他拿什么武器吗
Chief Monroe. Do you know what kind of weapon he has?
我一知道就告诉你  好吗?
I'll let you know when I know, okay?
你会是第一个知道的
You'll be the first to know.
我等下就告诉你
I'll let you know later.
真高兴看到你  葛斯
Good to see you, Gus.
你好  法兰  真受瞩目啊
How you doing, Frank? It's hot.
没错
Yeah, it is.
怎么回事?
So?
太早出动大批警力了吧?
It's early for the heavy artillery.
也许吧  也许不会
Maybe. Maybe not.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
你正目睹一切
You're looking at it.
里面有个很沮丧的父亲
Very upset father inside,
我们得给他几分钟冷静下来
so we're giving him a few minutes to cool off.
别给他太多时间了
Let's not give him too much time.
尽快解决这件事  好吗?
Let's end this quick and quiet. Okay?
这正是我们的计划
That's the plan.
好  很好
All right, good. Good.
那样的话  我就在此支援吧
In that case, I'm just here to lend my support.
我不需要保姆  不会有问题的
I don't need a babysitter, Gus. It's under control.
是吗?
Is it?
没错
Yes, it is.
好吧
All right.
街上不能有人持枪跑来跑去
Can't have people running around the street using guns, Frank.
那会让人觉得本市很危险
Make it look like the city's unsafe.
另外  我必须待在这里
Besides, I got to be here.
我不想让人以为局长在偷懒
Police chief doesn't show up, looks like he's asleep at the wheel.
那就别插手乱管
Well, just stay out of my way.
电视台的摄影机在那里
The TV cameras are over there.
那应该会让你觉得很自在
Should make you feel right at home.
是啊
Right.
你放轻松点嘛
Why don't you just relax?
你为何老是无法放轻松?
Why can't you relax?
我很好
I'm fine.
做你该做的事  我不会K你
Do your job. I'm not here to cut your nuts off.
我是在做啊
I'm doing my job.
我们都是警察  对吧?
We're both cops, right?
我们是站在同一边的  记得吧?
We're on the same side, remember?
对  对
Right, right, right.
好
Okay.
很高兴见到你  谢谢
It's good to see you. Thanks.
喂?  是的  市长先生
Hello? Yes, Mr. Mayor.
回头见了
I'll see you in a little bit.
不  我们了解...好  我知道
No, we got it...Okay. I got it.
老人家在找成人纸尿布
The old man looking for his Depends.
他是不是忘在这里了?
Did he lave them over here?
我不懂为何医生们没发现
I don't understand why they never found it, the doctors.
我儿子出生时健康的很
My son has had clean checkups since the day he was born.
医生为何没发现问题?
How could the doctors not pick it up?
他也许并未彻底检查
He might not have been tested thoroughly enough.
为什么?
Why not?
你加入的是HMO的保险吧?
You got an HMO, right?
对
Yeah.
答案就在这里
There's your answer.
HMO付钱请医生不要检查
HMOs pay their doctors not to test.
那样可以压低成本
That's the way. It keeps costs down.
假设麦克需要额外的检验
Say Mike did need additional testing,
但保险公司说他们不会付钱...
and insurance says they won't cover it...
医生就会闭上嘴...
the doctor keeps his mouth shut...
到了圣诞节
and come Christmas,
HMO就会寄分红支票给医生
the HMO sends the doctor a fat-ass bonus check.
真的吗?
Is that true?
有可能
Possible.
不一定  但有可能
Not likely, but possible.
这些医生可能早知道有问题...
These doctors my have known what was wrong...
他们本可以早些治疗他的?
and they could've treated him all along?
谁知道呢?  我不知道  约翰
Who knows? I don't know, John.
我这不是攻击你  医生
Don't take this personal, doc,
但医生真是一群骗子
but you all a bunch of goddamn crooks.
你别乱说话
You don't know what you're talking about.
你们发的誓又是怎么回事?
What about that thing that you guys take?
发誓?
The thing?
誓言啊  你们怎么说?
That promise. What do they call it?
医德伦理誓约
The Hippocratic oath.
比较像是伪君子誓约吧
More like the hypocritical oath.
那是怎么说的?
How's it go, doc?
我宣誓要照顾病患  尤其是濒死病患...
"I'll solemnly swear to take care of the sick, damned near dying...
除非他们没有保险
unless they ain't got major medical."
是这样说的吗?
Something like that?
你说的很正确  就是那样
You got it perfectly. That's it.
这很可笑  但这离事实不远了
Funny, but it's not far from the truth.
这种事常发生
This shit happens all the time.
急救人员送进急病伤患...
Paramedics bring in some accident victim...
当会计发现他们付不出钱
and when accounting finds out they can't pay,
就把他们送走
they send him packing.
医院不能拒绝病人
Hospitals can't turn people away.
没有法律能处罚他们吗?
Isn't there laws against that?
有  但他们有漏洞可钻
Yeah, but there's also ways around those laws.
我们只需要先稳住他们...
The only thing we have to do is stabilize them...
之后  我们就没责任了
and after that, we're off the hook.
事情不是这样的
That's not how it works.
事情就是这样
That's exactly how it works.
也许心脏外科不是  但在这里...
Maybe not on the fifth floor, but in here...
要是你没钱
no money,
会被乱医一通  然后被踢出去
you get a Band-Aid, a foot in the ass, and you're out the door.
闭嘴  够了
Shut up.
我已经听太多抱怨了
I've heard all the bitching I can stand for one day.
你们若要把我当成吸血鬼  好
If you all want to regard me as some kind of blood-sucking vampire, fine.
很好  我就当坏蛋吧
Great. I'll be the bad guy.
但是谁拿枪在要胁人的?
But who's holding the fucking gun?
长官
Sir!
副队长
Lieutenant!
喂?
Hello?
喂
Hello.
约翰  我是葛法兰
John, this is Frank Grimes.
线路被切了
The line is clipped.
你拿起电话就直通我这里
You pick up the phone, you get me. Okay?
有什么需要我帮忙的?
Now, what can I do for you?
名单的事怎么样了?
What's going on with the list?
我正在设法  但我需要时间
I'm working on it, but I need time.
我没时间  法兰
Time I don't have, Frank.
谈谈人质吧
Let's talk about the postages.
那就谈吧  你想知道什么?
What do you want to know?
里面情况如何?  他们好吗?
What's going on in there? How are they?
他们很好
They're fine.
我们又吃点心又讨论医疗保险
We seating candy bars and discussing HMOs.
我们在等你
We're waiting for you.
放一些人出来
Let some of them go.
为什么?
For what?
我帮你忙  你也该表现诚意
I do for you, you do for me. Show some good faith.
这里有很多人很紧张
A lot of nervous people here, John.
要是你能放几个人  大家会轻松一点
Make everybody breath a lot easier if we saw some happy faces.
等你开始帮忙以后再说
I'll do for you when you start doing for me.
我要我儿子登上名单
I want my kid's name on that list.
别耍我  法兰
I'm not kidding around, Frank.
表现诚意  约翰
Good faith, John.
诚意到此为止
Good faith only takes you so far.
那是什么?  他吗?
What's that? Him?
目前为止你还没有帮上忙
So far you haven't earned any points.
抱歉  我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
好
Yeah.
她撑开了六公分  胎位不正
She's six centimeters dilated, and the baby is breech.
我们得立刻把她送去产科
We have to move her to Maternity immediately.
约翰
John.
等等  法兰
Hang on, Frank.
在这里
Right down here.
怎么回事?
What the hell is going on?
认得这个人吗?
Do you know this man?
约翰·亚契  他儿子在加护病房
His name is John Archibald. He has a son in ICU.
派人去病房  我要跟母亲谈
Put people on the door. I need to talk to the mother.
你在吗  法兰?
Are you there, Frank.
我在  约翰
I'm here, John. I'm here.
我改变主意了
I changed my mind.
我要放一些人质
I'll let some of the hostages go.
很好  约翰  这样做很对
That's great, John.
但等我一开始放人
But when I do,
就开始计时了  明白吗?
the clock starts. You understand?
现在4点15
It's 4:15.
你有一小时  到5点15  懂吗
You got one hour. You got till 5:15. Understand, Frank.
要是我儿子到时没登上名单
If my boy's not on that list by 5:15,
就有人会丧命
somebody is going to die.
约翰  别做傻事
Don't be stupid.
5点15  法兰
5:15, Frank!
5点15分  快去设法
Five-one-five, something happens for me!
我明白了
Got it.
你是警察  快找验尸官吧
You're a cop. Call the coroner.
这太糟了  法兰
This is bad, Frank.
这一定要赶快解决
This has just got to go away.
好了  蜜丽
All right, Miriam.
放轻松  不会有事的
Relax, everything's going to be okay.
我们的宝贝会很好的  别担心
Our baby will be fine.
还有萝莎
And Rosa.
什么?
Yes?
走吧
Let's go.
亚契先生
Mr. Archibald?
请让我先生一起走
Please let my husband come with me.
不  你先出去  我不会有事的
Baby, no, I need you to get out of here. I'll be okay.
我走好了  我无牵无挂
Shit, I'll go. I'm free.
史提  不要
Steve, no.
你算不算男人啊?
What kind of man are you?
去你的  黑金刚
Screw you, Tyrone.
什么?  去我的?  黑金刚?
What? Screw me, Tyrone?
去我的?!
Screw me?!
等等  别激动...
Wait a minute, all right? Just relax...
干的好  大老粗
That's right, tough guy.
朱莉  宝贝  快拿枪
Julie, baby, get the gun!
快捡起枪
Pick up that gun!
快射他  朝他的脸开枪
Now, shoot him! Shoot him right in the face, Julie!
朝他的脸开枪  快拿枪
Shoot him right in the face! Get the gun!
拿枪啊
Get the gun.
干嘛  你疯了?
What, are you crazy?!
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?!
快住手
Come on, now!
麦斯  你有手铐吗?
Max, you got cuffs?
有
Yeah.
天啊
Oh, God!
你这个蠢贱货
You stupid bitch!
那是因为你海扁我
That's for beating the shit out of me!
那是因为你混蛋透顶
And that's for being an asshole!
这个呢?
And this?
这是因为你叫我贱货
This is for calling me a bitch!
好痛啊
I felt that one.
我不会再当你的芭比娃娃了
And I'm not going to go your Barbie anymore.
好耶  宝贝
Goddamn, baby!
你真是又辣又带劲
All that ass and muscles to go with it.
我就知道你不是金发妞
I knew damn well you wasn't no blond.
过来
Come here.
你们俩个  走吧
Let's go, both of you.
不管怎样
Whatever happens,
我要你知道一切会很顺利
I want you to know everything's going to be okay.
懂吗?
Understand?
我懂
Yes.
别担心
Don't worry.
好
Okay.
别瞎操心
Don't worry about anything.
我会永远在你身边
I'll always be there for you.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
我要释放人质  别开枪
I'm letting some hostages go! Don't shoot!
好  你们俩个
All right, you two.
走吧  你们俩个
Let's go, both of you.
谢谢你  谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
好了  萝莎  你也是
All right, all right. Rose, you too.
好  好好照顾小孩
All right, Take care of the baby.
持枪暴徒刚刚放了几个人质...
The gunman has just freed several hostages...
他们将会接受专案小组讯问
who will be debriefed by the crisis team.
约翰老Q能帮小孩弄到心脏吗?
Will John Q. Get a heart for his little boy?
时间会证明一切  记者在医院...
Only time will tell. From Hope Memorial Hospital...
持枪暴徒掌控急诊室之后
Is it true a gunshot victim was dropped off.
是否真有枪伤病患被送进去?
After the gunman took over the E.R?
对  他让他进去的
Yes. He let him inside.
请说句话  先生
Can you comment, sir?
那个人伤的很重
The man was critically injured.
要不是他让他进去  他死定了
If he hadn't let him in, he would've died.
太太  你还好吧?
Ma'am. Are you all right?
我很好  我们的孩子快诞生了
Oh, yeah, I feel good. We're having a baby!
太太  你对持枪暴徒有何看法
Ma'am, do you have any comments about the gunman?
约翰老Q  很好的人
John Q., very good man.
持枪暴徒?
The gunman?
很好的人
Very good man.
里面有摄影机
They got a camera in there.
他们在看拍到的画面
They're watching a video feed.
你怎么知道?
How do you know that?
他们在看东西
They're looking at something, Freddy.
能弄到吗?
Can you get it?
老大  他们有的我都弄得到
Boss, if they got it, I can get it.
你让步  暴徒会充斥全国医院
You give in, there'll be guns in every hospital in the country.
又不是只有他家小孩生病
Do you think Mr. Archibald's the only one who has a sick child?
去爱滋病房看  整层楼都是
Ever checked out the HIV ward? There's a whole floor of them.
人会生老病死  人生就是如此
People get sick, they die, that's the way it goes.
我每天都面临这样的决策
I face decisions like this every day.
有人威胁要杀死无辜的人们
A man's threatening to kill innocent people.
就因为你不帮助他儿子
Because you didn't help his son.
拜托  这国家有五千万人
There are 50 million people in this country.
没有医疗保险
Without medical insurance.
想改变这情况  去找国会议员
If you'd like to change it, you should call your congressman.
抱歉
Excuse me.
何不告诉他  他儿子在名单上
Why don't we just tell him his son's name's on the list?
那不是很好吗?
I mean, doesn't that make sense?
他反正也不会知道真相
How's he going to know, anyway?
长官  抱歉  请你过来看看
Sir? Pardon me, can you come take a look at this?
这是皮华利  保安主管
Sarge, Chief, this is Wally Pitoniak, head of security.
你好
How are you?
幸会
Nice to meet you.
我帮你找到狙击点
I got your spot.
你们在这里
Here's your site.
那里就是最好的点
That's going to be your perch.
X代表你的电话
The X is your phone.
哪只电话?
Which phone?
靠近一点
Bring it up, Jeff.
那里那只电话
That phone right there.
是的  汤姆
It is, Tom.
孟局长仍说会采取必要行动
But Chief Monroe maintains that police will do what's necessary.
以确保人质的生命与安全
to preserve the lives and safety of these hostages.
这个国家
This country, man.
不管去到哪里
Can't go anymore.
都会被抢  被杀或是被刺
Without getting mugged, or murdered, or stabbed.
小孩子枪杀同学...
Kids killing their classmates, drive-by...
我甚至不敢再去邮局了
I won't even go into a post office anymore.
闭嘴  米区
Shut up, Mitch!
你才闭嘴
You shut up!
我恨那个混蛋  但他说的对
I hate the bastard, but he's right.
知道要弄到枪有多容易吗?
You know how easy it is to get a gun?
五分钟  在枪展上...
Five minutes, gun show...
我明白你孩子病了
I understand that your kid is sick, John.
但这算什么  我也有人生啊
But what makes him better than me? I get a life too.
对  但你有保险
Yeah, but you got insurance.
所以你要开枪?  你跟警察说的
So you're going to shoot me? That's what you're telling the cops.
要是你儿子没得到心脏
If your son doesn't the very first heart available.
我们就死定了
We all die.
结局会怎样?
How's it going to end, John?
你打算怎么办?
What's your move?
我不打算怎样  我不知道
I got no move, okay? I don't know what I'm going to do.
我在等待奇迹  好吗?
I'm waiting on a miracle, okay?
我在等待上帝的旨意
I'm waiting on an act of God.
亚契太太?
Mrs. Archibald?
我们可以谈谈吗?
Could we have a word with you, please?
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
医院告诉我要麦克出院时...
When the hospital told me they were releasing Mikey...
我打给约翰  对他乱吼
I called John and I yelled at him.
还叫他要采取行动
And told him to do something, anything.
但我没想到...
But, I never thought...
我明白
I understand.
他有暴力倾向吗?
Is he a violent man, Mrs. Archibald?
没有  他温柔又亲切
No, no, he's sweet and gentle.
他连小虫都不敢打
He wouldn't hurt a fly.
他可不这么说  他说要杀人
That's not what he's saying. He's talking about killing people.
我想知道的是我可能多心了...
Now, what I want to know is...I may be fishing here...
他是否在部队待过或什么的?
but has he spent any time in the military or anything like that?
这是在干嘛?
What is this?
什么?
What?
我知道了
I see what's going on here.
你想从我口中套话
You want me to say something.
好让你拿来对付我丈夫
That you can use against my husband.
他的麻烦大了
He's in a lot of trouble.
我们需要你去跟他谈谈
And we're going to need you to talk to him.
我们把话说明白点吧
Let's get something straight, mister.
你不能利用我去对付我丈夫
You cannot use me to build a case against my husband.
我支持他所做的每一件事
I support him in everything that he does.
我站在他那边  不是你这边
I'm on his side, not yours.
亚契太太
Mrs. Archibald.
你别跟我说话
And you don't talk to me!
我可以说出我对你的看法...
I would tell you what I think of you...
但我是虔诚的教徒
but I'm a Christian woman.
请你们俩个离开
Now, you two leave me alone.
我还要照顾我生病的孩子
I have a sick child to look after.
我已决定把麦克列入名单
I've decided to put Michael on the recipient list.
医院会负担所有费用
The hospital will pay for everything.
真的?
Really?
真的
Really.
谢谢你
Thank you.
天啊  谢谢你
Oh, God, thank you!
你真行
You're good.
什么?
Excuse me?
表演的真棒
Quite the performance.
温暖的拥抱  诚挚的表情
The comforting embrace, the sincere look.
那一刹那  我真的相信你了
For a minute, I actually believed that you cared.
记者塔克在希望纪念医院
We go now to Hope Memorial Hospital live.
为您现场报导
Tuck Lampley.
在医院前的群众越聚越多
The crowd in front of Hope Memorial is growing.
特勤小组已经到达现场
The SWAT team has arrived.
现场情况变得相当紧张
And the situation is becoming very tense.
站在我身旁的是詹姆士·帕波
Standing next to me is James Palumbo.
约翰·亚契的朋友
Friend of John Archibald.
帕波先生  谈谈亚契先生吧
Mr. Palumbo, what can you tell us about John Archibald?
你知道...
You know...
我必须诚实  塔克
I got to be honest, Tuck.
这整件事真是可怕
This whole thing sucks, you know?
其实这都是可以避免的
It all could've been avoided so incredibly easy.
要是约翰是富翁就不会这样
None of this had to happen if John had been a millionaire.
他是石油大亨就好 但他不了解
Or, if his name was Rockefeller, but sometimes John don't get it.
这国家尊重的不是价值
He don't understand that. What we hold sacred in this country isn't values.
重要的是价钱
It's value that's important.
我们有富人也有穷人
We got haves, we got have-nots.
有白领  蓝领阶级  有失业的
We got white-collar, blue-collar, and then we got no-collar.
所以医院
Inside there.
有豪华手术也有阳春手术...
We got surgery, we got outpatient surgery...
还有烂手术
and we got out-of-luck surgery.
这社会有很多人
There's a lot of people out there, Tuck.
很多根本没有25万的人
A lot of people here who don't got 250 grand.
把这样的人逼到绝境真是可耻...
To shame a man like that and back him into a corner...
在我看来
seems to me.
这是社会制度失序
Something is out of whack not someone.
我懂什么?  我只是个工人
What do I know? I'm a factory worker.
看得出来这事令你很难过...
I can see this is making you very upset...
但你若能面对镜头对约翰说话
but, if you could speak to John Q. Right now.
你要说什么?
What would you say?
"詹姆士·帕波  约翰的友人"
我与你同在  你要保重
I'm there with you, and you take care.
这是一个朋友的心声
That's one man's opinion.
这是记者塔克的报导
Live at the crisis at Hope Memorial, this is Tuck Lampley.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
副队长  人呢?
Were is everybody?
我们要派人从通风管进去
We're sending a guy in through the air duct.
要是能让目标到这电话旁
If we can get the target to this phone,
我们就能动手射杀他
we got a clear shot.
是吗?
Is that right?
是的  副队长  没错
Yes, lieutenant, that is right.
就等你下令了  局长
When you're ready, chief.
别紧张  各位
Don't be nervous, guys.
老孟
Monroe!
我老婆要开骂了
My wife's calling.
更糟  是老爸要训话了
Worse, chief, it's Father Time.
你给我过来
Come over here!
别说了  法兰  我不想听...
Not one word, Frank. Not one word, I don't want to hear...
你这混蛋  在我背后搞小动作
You son of bitch! You're going behind my back!
你要我怎么办?  你看看时间
What do you want from me, Frank? Look at the clock!
看看你的表
Look at your watch!
那家伙说一刻钟后就要开杀戒...
The guy said at a quarter after, he's going o start killing peple...
这太愚蠢了
This is so goddamn stupid!
那你有什么好主意?
Then, what's your great idea?!
没什么好主意  特别是这个
There are no great ideas, especially this!
我有机会逮这家伙  我要动手
I got a shot at this guy, and I'm going to take it!
你做事老是不明快  你在说什么
You always take the open shot! What are you talking about?!
他老婆同意要跟他谈  让她来
The wife has agreed to speak to him! Let her talk him down.
我正打算这么做
That's exactly what I'm going to do.
利用他老婆逮他?
Use the man's wife to set him up?
什么有用我就用什么
I'll use whatever work, Frnak.
我帮你描绘一下吧
Let me paint a picture for you.
这是一个双输的局面
Ok, what we have here is a lose/lose.
要是他开始杀人质  就糟了
If he starts whacking hostages, it's bad!
但我们若向他投降  也很糟
And if we give in to this asshole it's also bad!
对谁很糟?
Bad for who?
对大家都很糟  你  我  大家
It's bad for everybody! Me, you, everybody!
今年是选举年  就是很糟
It's an election year, it's just bad!
不管怎样  这家伙不能成功
However it goes down, Frank, this guy's not going to make it!
你要杀他?  为选举铺路?
So you kill him? That's a P.R. Bonanza, right?!
死一个坏蛋没什么
I can live with one dead bad guy!
我忍受不了的是
What I can't live with.
有无辜的市民受伤
Is one innocent person being hurt!
不能在我任内
Not one! Not on my watch!
法兰  你出局了
You know what, Frank? You're out!
我出局了?
I'm out?!
与个人无关  但你被停职了
No hard feelings, but you're relieved of duty.
从现在起由我主导
I'll handle this now.
你?
You?
对  我
Yeah, me.
你以为我这是第一次指挥?
Think it's my first time in the dance floor?
你以为我是怎么得到这些的?
How do you think I got these?
小心点  别惹我
And watch it! Just watch it!
我承受很多压力  很多人在看
I got a lot of pressure on me, Frank. A lot of eye's watching.
总要有人行动  而你不行动
Someone's got to make the call. You're not going to do it!
那就由我来
I'll do it.
那些人质怎么办?
What about the hostages, the human beings?!
他们最好小心点
Better keep their heads down.
太好了
Great.
怎么回事?
What is it?
空调停了
The air-conditioning just turned off.
就靠你了  别让我失望
I'm counting on you, don't let me down.
我再打电话给你
I'll call you.
好耶  借过
Right on. Excuse me.
别碰我  借过  谢谢
Don't touch me. Excuse me. Thank you.
蓝塔克  第八频道的
Tuck Lampley, channel eight.
好
All right. You get it.
谢了  警官  借过
Thanks, officer! Excuse me.
我知道
I know.
我的画面呢?
Where's my picture?
快好了  我才刚破解警方密码
It's coming. I just got to unscramble the police encryption, almost there.
快点  我跟心脏科的人联系过
Hurry up. I got a contact in Cardiology.
警方要让这家伙跟他太太通话
The cops are setting up a phone call between this guy and his wife.
他太太在你旁边吗?
Are you with the wife?
好  接通吧
All right, let's patch it through.
喂?
Hello?
你最好有好消息要说  法兰
This better be good, Frank.
约翰?
John?
狄妮?
Denise?
宝贝
Hi, baby.
我们上了名单了
We're on the list.
什么?
What?
潘小姐刚离开这里
Payne just left here.
麦克名字列上了  你成功了
Mikey's name is on the list. Baby, you did it!
我们在名单上了?
We're on the list?
好啊
Okay.
这太棒了
This is great, baby!
好耶
Yeah!
有声音了
We got sound!
很好
Good.
影像呢?  拜托  我要画面
But where's the video? Come on, I need picture!
等等  我会让你出名的
Hang on. I'm going to make you famous.
很好  宝贝
It's okay, baby.
麦克好吗?
How's Mikey doing?
不太好
Not too good.
我想他快死了
I think he's going away.
什么?
What?
他们已经尽力了...
They've done everything they can for him...
但他的情况还是越来越糟
but he keeps getting worse.
"希望纪念医院人质危机"
天啊
Oh, God!
可怜的小乖
Our poor baby!
你有为他祷告吗?
Are you praying for him, John?
你有为我们的小乖祷告吗?
Are you praying for our baby?
我有  甜心  你知道我有的
Yes, I'm praying, sweetheart. You know I am.
将军
Checkmate.
总部  听见吗?
White Rook, copy?
听见了
I copy, White Rook.
不会有事的  听我说
It'll be all right, sweetheart. Listen to me.
他会活下来的
He'll make it.
我以我的性命发誓
I swear on my life.
他会活下来的  明白吗?
He's going to make it, you understand me?
好
Okay.
你必须相信我  懂吗?
You just got to believe me, you understand?
我相信
I believe.
麦克睡了?  能跟他说话吗?
Is Mikey awake? Can I talk to him?
等等
Hold on.
我的老天
Oh, my God.
弄到了  老大  有影像了
We got it! Boss, we got it! The video's on-line.
你真行
You are beautiful.
我弄到监视器画面了
I got to get the monitor.
你还站在这里干嘛?
What are you doing standing around?
快点  机不可失啊
Come on, man! This is it!
谢谢你
Thank you.
佛瑞  我发誓  我...
Freddy, I swear to God, I'm...
奈吉  你动作真慢  快一点
Nigel, you're moving like lava, hustle!
我的发型怎样?  算了  快开始
How's my hair? Never mind, let's got this.
三  二  一...
Three, two, one...
蓝塔克在希望纪念医院
Tuck Lampley, at Hope Memorial Hospital
为各位带来独家报导...
bringing you exclusive coverage...
关于一对父子
between a father and a son,
父亲正设法想救儿子一命
he's fighting desperately to save.
小乖  你爸在电话线上
Honey, your daddy's on the phone.
喂?
Hello?
冠军
Champ.
我的小乖好吗?
How's my boy?
你还在努力吗?
You hanging in there?
你好吗?
How are you?
我好吗?  我很好
How am I? I'm good.
别担心我  我很好
Don't worry about me, I'm good.
爸  你为什么没来?
How come you're not here, Dad?
我很忙  麦克  我现在走不开...
I'm tied up, Mikey. I can't get away right now...
但我离你很近
but I'm close.
真的很近
I'm real close to you.
妈说我需要一颗新的心脏
Mom says I need a new heart.
没错  你是需要
Yeah, that's right, champ, you do.
我的心怎么了?
But, what's wrong with my heart?
没有  没什么
No, it's nothing wrong.
只是你...
It's just that you...
你需要...
You just need a...
需要更好的心脏好让你更强壮
You got to get a better heart to be stronger, that's all.
他们会给你一颗新的心
They'll give you a new one.
那会让你变得很强壮
It's going to make you real strong.
好
Okay.
好吗?
Okay?
爸?
Hey, Dad?
什么事?
Yeah?
我会死吗?
Am I going to die?
不  你不会死  当然不会
No, you're not going to die. Of course not.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
这世界没有你还有什么乐趣?
Hey, what good would the world be without you?
这是我看过最棒的报导了
This is the greatest thing I've ever seen.
没有你  这世界毫无意义
Without you, there is no world.
这就是我的金钟奖了
This is my white bronco.
麦克
Hey, Mike.
听我说
Listen to me.
等你下令了
On your command.
你知道我爱你吧?
You know I love you, don't you?
你知道我很以你为荣吧?
You know how proud I am of you?
知道
Yeah.
我只是想确定你知道
I just want to make sure you know that.
我想告诉你  以免我忘了说
I just wanted to tell you that, in case I forgot.
动手吧
Take the shot.
不行
Not clear.
准备
Holding.
来一个强棒高手的招牌动作吧
Why don't you give me one of those Chris Cormier's?
好耶
Yeah!
好耶  强棒高手
Yeah. Chris Cormier.
他真棒
He's great.
他是很棒  你也是
He's great. So are you, baby.
我爱你  爸
I love you, Dad.
很好  儿子
Okay, son.
我待会再打电话给你
I'll talk to you later, okay?
说真的  我爱你
With all my heart son, I love you.
我也爱你  爸
I love you too, Dad.
妈的
Oh, Shot!
你上电视了
You on TV, man!
第八频道
Channel eight!
射中了  他挂了
He's down. We got him.
他挂了
He's down.
他没挂
He's not down.
该死
Goddamn it!
这真是糟糕啊
This is very bad, Gus.
长官
Sir.
现在不要
Not now!
长官  是市长
No, sir, it's the mayor, sir.
我们最好切掉监视画面
And we better kill this video feed.
媒体截走讯号
The press hacked our signal.
这成了全国新闻联播画面
This just went out live over national television.
麦克活不了了
Mikey's not going to make it.
他不是上名单了?
What about the list?
什么名单?  他们向我开枪
What list? They're shooting at me.
向我们开枪
They're shooting us.
他们不会救我儿子的
They're not going to help my son.
显然  狙击手潜进医院
Apparently, the sniper gained access to the hospital through the-
你要逮捕我?
You're going to bust me?
出去
You're out of here.
注意点  你们刚在电视上杀人
Get real. You just shot an innocent man on prime-time TV.
姓葛的呢?
Where's Grimes?
我要见葛法兰
I want to see Frank Grimes.
等等
Hang in there, man.
葛副队长呢?
Where's Lieutenant Grimes?!
好吧
All right.
好什么?
All right, what?
去看看他要什么
Let's see what he wants.
你在说笑
You're got to be kidding.
别为难我了  我搞砸了
Don't start breaking my balls. I screwed up.
我需要你帮忙
I need you to say my ass.
我搞砸了  求求你  法兰
I stepped in shit. Lease, Frank.
拜托  我请你吃牛排吧
Come on. I'll buy you a steak.
北京烤鸭
Peking duck.
好  没问题
You got it.
走吧
Let's go.
亚洲的亚  契约的契
A-R-C-H-l-B-A-L-D.
我现在就把资料传给你
I'm faxing you all the stuff right now.
好  来吧  快把这事解决
Okay, come on in. Let's clear this up.
别开火
Hold your fire!
别开火  把枪放下  放下
Don't fire. Turn them down. Turn them down.
这里有很多摄影机  别做傻事
There's a lot of cameras. I don't want anybody doing anything.
跟你来的是谁?
Who's that with you?
穆警官
Sergeant Moody.
警察局的孟局长
Police Chief Monroe.
这是怎么回事  约翰?
What's going on here, John?
他没穿裤子
He's got no pants on.
你骗我  副队长
You lied to me, lieutenant.
你说你会给我回报  但你没有
You said you'd call back, Frank, but you didn't call.
我放了人质给你
I give you your hostages.
但你却没给我回报
But you didn't call me back. Why?
因为你要我死
Because you want me dead.
没有人想要你死  约翰
Nobody wants to kill you, John.
没有人想要我死?
Nobody wants to kill me?
没有
No.
没有?
Nobody?
没有
No.
这些人也不想?  他也不想?
None if these guys? Not him?
不想
No.
好  那这是什么
Okay, what is this?
这是什么?
What is this?
你以为情况会变成怎样?
What did you think would happen?
你想知道实情?  这就是实情
You want truth? Here's some truth.
事情终将会对你不利的
This is going to end bad for you, John.
你只有两条出路
There's only two ways out of here.
去坐牢...
Jail...
或是没命
or dead.
我儿子病的很重
My son is very sick.
他需要人帮忙
And he needs some help.
我明白
I understand.
这年头做人很难
It's hard to be a man these days.
很难知道该怎么做才对
Hard to know what the right thing is.
但请你放下枪
But put the gun, John.
你没听我说  我儿子病了
You're not hearing me, Frank! My son is sick!
就这样  没别的了
That's it! There's nothing else!
结束
End of story!
人们生病  就需要帮忙
When people are sick, they deserve a little help.
好耶
Yeah!
生病  帮忙
Sick, Help!
我不打算帮我儿子送葬
I am not going to bury my son!
我儿子才会帮我送葬
My son is going to bury me.
你以为这些人在乎你?  才不呢
You think these people give a shit about you? They don't.
你只是暂时的新闻焦点
You're the cause if the moment.
没有人在乎  这才是事实
Nobody cares, John. That's the real truth.
没有人在乎  只有你在乎
Nobody cares. Only you.
只有你跟我...
And it's only you and out here...
还有这些指着你的枪
and all these guns pointed at you.
你要怎么做?  由你决定
So, what do you want to do? It's your call.
我要我儿子
I want my son.
我要我儿子进来陪我
I want my son inside with me!
不行
Can't do it, John.
把我儿子送来  我就放了枪手
You give my boy, I give you your sniper.
一切就结束
Then it's all over.
把我儿子送来...
You bring my son...
我投降
I give up.
大家都回家
everybody goes home.
大家也都平安无事
Everybody's safe.
把我儿子送来
You bring me my son.
走吧
Come on.
好吧
All right.
你觉得如何?
What do you think, Frank?
我想就送给他吧
I say give it to him.
他儿子进去  他就不会杀人
He won't hurt anybody with his boy in here.
我们要救人质  不是送人质
The object is get hostages out, not to bring them in.
那不是人质  那是他儿子
It's not a hostage. It's his son.
这些人都没看过新闻吗?
Have all these people been on the new?
看你的了  法兰
It's your call, Frank.
好
Yeah.
好吧  把他送进去
All right, give it to him.
停  不行
Hold it. No-N-No.
我是他母亲  我要跟着去
I'm his mother. I need to be in there!
别过来  停
Stop right there. Stop.
走开  快走开
Go. Beat it. Go.
快  快
Go! Go!
麻烦大了  约翰
We're in trouble, John.
麦克的血压降到四十几了
Mike's blood pressure's dropped into the mid-40's.
心房血压应该只有十几
His atrial blood pressure should be in the low teens.
现在是35
It's 35.
对不起  约翰
I'm sorry, John.
没有新的心脏...
Without a new heart...
他是活不了的
he's not going to make it.
好吧
Okay.
就用我的
You take mine.
什么?
What?
你听见了
You heard me.
拿我的心脏给麦克用
Take my heart and you put it in Mike.
老兄  你真是疯了
Man, you done lost your damn mind.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
我是认真的  我很认真
You bet I'm serious. I'm dead serious.
老天爷
Oh, my God.
那意味着你会死
That means you'll be dead.
而我儿子会活
And my son will live.
你不能这么做
You can't do this.
这是唯一的方法
It's the only way.
你不懂  生理上你不能这么做
No, physically, you can't do this.
我可以  我杀了自己
Yes, I can. I kill myself.
你剖开我  拿走心脏  很完美
You open me up, you take my heart. It's perfect.
天  这疯狂了
Man, that's just crazy.
不能这样就把你的心移给麦克
No, we can't just remove your heart and put it in Michael's body.
还有很多未知因素
Too many unknowns.
捐赠者跟受赠者的比对程序复杂
Matching a donor and a recipient is complicated.
有很多重要的检验要做
There are critical tests to be done.
比方说呢?
Like what?
互相比对血型  胸腔大小
Cross-matches for blood type, chest cavity measurements.
要是血型不符
If both blood tissues are not compatible.
我都知道  我们仔细比对过
I know all about compatibility.
我们都是B型阳性  组织吻合...
We're both B-positive, our tissues match...
他心脏比正常大三倍 我的可以
his heart's three times the size of a normal, so will fit.
你知道我们很合
You know we're compatible.
这是不可能的
It's out of the question.
医生  我说可以
Doc, I'm telling you he will make it.
不行  约翰  不行
Can't do it. John. No.
要是我死了
So if I'm dead.
你也不会拿我的心去救他?
You're not going to take heart and save his life?
你宁可让两个人死也不动手?
You'll let two people die instead of one because of a technicality?
我认为约翰是对的
I think what John is trying to do is right.
我认为他很勇敢
I think it's so brave.
麦克会想要吗?  你太太呢?
What do you think Mike would want? What about your wife?
麦克还小  他不懂什么对他好
Mike's too young to know what's good for him.
我是他父亲  我有责任保护他
I'm his father. It's my job to protect him.
何况  狄妮也会做一样的事
Besides, Denise would do the same thing.
约翰  听着
John, look.
我知道麦克的情况很不好
I know what's happening to Mike is bad, man.
事实上  根本就很糟
Matter of fact, it's the worst.
但自杀并不能解决事情
But killing yourself ain't going to solve a damn thing.
有时你必须放手
Sometimes you just got to let go.
让上帝接手
And let God.
接受它吧  兄弟
Just accept it, brother.
接受它
Accept it.
接受什么?
Accept what?
麦克会死
That Mike is going to die.
不  我不接受
No, I don't accept that.
绝不
Ever!
我绝对不接受  听着
No, I reject that out of hand. I mean, look.
他对你而言只是病人  我明白
All right, he's a patient to you. I understand.
他是个好孩子
He's a good kid.
他喜欢健身
I mean, he loves bodybuilding.
他想当健美先生  你相信吗?
He wants to be a bodybuilder. Can you believe that?
他也很幽默  你会喜欢他的
And he's funny. You' d like him.
你会喜欢他的  若你能认识他
You'd like him, doc, if you got to know him.
我是很喜欢他
I do like him. All right, then.
那就求求你  我求你
Then please, I'm just begging you.
别管那些规定了
Step outside the rules.
我想  我真的很想
I'd like to, John. I really would.
但你的请求太过份了
But what you're asking crosses the line.
这完全是不道德的
It is completely unethical.
我太过份?  你才太过份了
I'm crossing he line? You're crossing the line.
整个制度都太过份了  谁在乎
The whole system crossing the line. Who cares?
也许你不明白我在说什么
Maybe you don' understand what I'm talking about.
我不在乎  我儿子要活下去
I don't give a damn. My son's going to live.
也许你还没搞清楚
Maybe you haven't figured it out.
我会尽一切力量让他活下去
I'll do whatever I got to do for him to live.
那你打算怎么办?
So, what are you going to do?
我不动手术你就杀我?
You're going to shoot me if I don't operate?
不
No.
我会自杀
I'll kill myself.
好吗?
All right?
看事情会怎么样
Let's just see what happens.
不就是这样吗?  他需要捐赠人
That's what this is all about, right? He needs donate
总要有人死  好让他活
Somebody's got to die in order for him to live.
我是他父亲  就是我了
I'm his father. It's me.
好吧
All right.
好吧?  好什么?
All right? All right what?
你想要我动手就动手吧
I'll do it if that's what you want.
你是说你要让他自杀?
You'll let him kill himself?
他若死了  有何不可?
Once he's dead, why not?
你是我认识最好的外科医生
You are the finest surgeon I know.
你不能为这人搞砸你的事业
You cannot throw your career away for this man.
医生  你动手就完了
Doctor, if you do this, you're finished.
他们会怎样?  告我吗?
What are they going to do? Sue me?
吊销执照?
Disbar me?
把我赶出俱乐部
Evict me from the country club?
不  这里还是医院
No. This is still a hospital.
只要有心脏可用
If there's a heart available.
我就不能浪费它
I'm not going to let it go to waste.
医生  麦先生  准备手术
Doctor, Mr. Maguire, let's get ready for surgery.
准备收成吧
Get ready to harvest.
好  快点  各位
All right, hurry up, guys.
把她放上手术台
Get her on the table.
有多少时间?
What's our time?
准备抬起来
Ready to lift.
45分
Oh-four-five.
摊开手术刀
Scalpels laid out.
托盘呢?  你有吗?
Where's the tray? You have the other in front of you?
把车推进来
Bring the cart around, please.
情况如何?
What do we have?
女性捐赠者
Female donor.
26岁...
26 years old...
身高五尺七吋
five-foot-seven.
肝脏  肾脏堪用
Liver, kidneys usable.
肝脏  肾脏都堪用
Liver and kidneys are both usable.
肺脏呢?
Lungs?
很好
Okay.
肺脏很好
Lungs are okay.
心脏呢?
Heart?
心脏很好
Heart is good.
心脏很好  血型?
Heart is good. Blood type?
B型阳性
B-positive.
这是我的...
This is my...
我的遗嘱
my will.
上面写我自愿把心脏给我儿子
It says I'm leaving my heart to my son,
我需要两个证人签名
And I need two witnesses to sign.
我不要签
I'm not signing that.
我才不要看着你自杀
I ain't going to watch you kill yourself.
我也是
Me neither.
你们越快签  就越快回家
The sooner you sign it, the sooner you go home.
好  我签
Okay. I'll sign.
我也是
Me too.
好了
Okay.
你就这样进去轰了自己?
You're just going to go in there and off yourself?
只有一件事能阻止我
Only one thing will stop me.
什么事?
What's that?
如果米区血型是B型阳性
If Mitch is B-positive.
不是  是O型  我发誓
No, no, no. Type O, swear to God.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你要保重
You be good. Be careful.
等着上报吧
See you in the funny papers.
我能跟他谈谈吗?
Can I have a word with him?
谢谢你
Thank you.
麦克
Hey, Mike.
Mikey.
你好吗?
How you doing, buddy?
爸
Hey, Dad.
你帮我弄到新的心脏了?
Did you bring me a new heart?
是啊  弄到了
Yeah, we got you one.
你一定是命中有贵人
I guess you got a guardian angel.
麦克  先别睡着  好吗?
Mike, try to stay awake for a minute, okay?
我要跟你说一些事
I just need to tell you a few things.
好
Okay, Dad.
你要听你妈的话
You always listen to your mother.
你明白吗
You understand?
照她说话的去做
Do what she tells you to do.
她是你最要好的朋友
She's your best friend.
每天都要告诉她你爱她
Tell her you love her every day.
好
Okay, Dad.
你现在交女朋友还太早...
You're too young for girls right now...
但时候总是会到的
but there's going to come a time.
到时候
And when it does.
你要像公主般对待她们...
You treat them like princesses...
因为她们就是公主
because that's what they are.
当你说要做什么...
When you say you're going to do something...
当你说要做什么时  一定要做
When you say you're going to do something, you do it.
因为你是言出必行的人
Because your word is your bond, son.
你一定要这样
It's all you have.
还有钱  有机会就要赚钱
And money. You make money if you get a chance.
纵使你必须偶尔昧着良心
Even if you got to sell out once in a while.
你也要设法赚钱
Make as much money as you can.
别跟你爸一样笨
Don't be stupid like your father.
好
Okay.
有钱会让你过得更顺利
Everything is so much easier with money, son.
别抽烟
Don't smoke.
对人要友善
Be kind to people.
要是有人杠上你
If somebody chooses you.
你要面对他  要像个男人
You stand up, you be a man.
别靠近不好的东西  拜托
You stay away from the bad things, son. Please.
别跟坏东西沾上边
Don't get caught up in the bad things.
世上有很多美好的事物等着你
There's so many great thing out there for you.
我永远不会离开你的
I'll never leave you.
我永远与你同在
I'm always with you.
就在这里
Right there.
我爱你
I love you, son.
回头见了
I'll see you later.
"麦克·亚契"
我的老天爷
Oh, my sweet Jesus.
好  动手吧
Okay, let's do it.
等等  那枪一直都没装子弹?
Wait a minute. You gun was empty the whole time?
对  我只是唬人
Yeah, I'm all talk.
我只想过要杀掉自己
The only one I ever considered to kill is me.
也许我们该拿些毛巾垫着
Maybe we should get some towels.
潘小姐  潘小姐
Miss Payne! Miss Payne?
什么事?
Yeah?
你不会相信的
You're not going to believe this.
什么?
What?
比对吻合了
We got a match.
B型阳性  麦克亚契
B-positive, Michael William Archibald.
全国唯一吻合的一级病患
The only status-one in the country.
我的天啊
I'll be damned.
我好渴
I'm thirsty.
亚契太太?
Mrs. Archibald?
我们有好消息
We have very good news.
老天爷
Oh, Jesus.
保险没开
The safety's on.
这是真的吗?
Is this for real?
飞机刚降落在芝加哥机场
The Learjet just landed at O'Hare.
直升机15分钟内就送到了
The helicopter will be here in 15 minutes.
这荣耀归你  好吗?
You do the honors, okay?
好  说吧
Okay, go?
约翰  是我
John, baby, it's me.
约翰
John.
这没用  约翰?
It's not working. John?
拜托  接起来  约翰...
Please, baby, pick up! John, can you...
约翰
John.
约翰  这是奇迹  有心脏了
John! It's a miracle, baby! They found a heart!
John, it's a miracle! They found a heart!
心脏送到了
The heart is here.
重覆  小麦克的心脏送来了
I repeat, the heart for little Mike Archibald has arrived.
这真是个不可思议的结局
What an unbelievable ending to this incredible, tumultuous day.
来了
Okay, here we go.
没错  人质们陆续出来了
Yes, the hostages are coming out.
一个  两个...
One, two...
他们历经痛苦折磨似乎累坏了
They appear to be exhausted from what must've been an excruciating ordeal.
出来更多人了  挥着手
More coming out. Hands waved in the air.
自由  终于自由了
Freedom, freedom at last.
警方护送他们到安全的地方
The police are escorting them to safety.
你们有什么感觉?
How do you feel?
大家都出来了  这是约翰
Somebody else is coming. It's John Q.
约翰出来了  他高举双手
John Q has come out, hand in the air.
他把枪放下了  似乎要投降
He's putting the gun down. He appears to be surrendering.
干的好  约翰
Way to go, John!
警方小心的接近他
The police are approaching.
他们逮住他了  他们压制了约翰
And they've got him. They've subdued John Q.
铐上手铐  一切似乎结束了
The handcuffs are on and it appears to be over.
完全落幕了
It's all over.
若说画面能代表千言万语
If pictures speak a thousand words.
这些影像更能令人感受到震撼
Then these images do speak volumes.
现在  事件落幕  提醒您...
And now, as the bloody standoff comes to an end, we remind you...
第八频道是第一个
that channel eight was here first,
独家赶到现场连线报导的频道...
with moment-to-moment live coverage...
这是希望纪念医院的危机报导
of "crisis at Hope Memorial."
我是蓝塔克
I'm Tuck Lampley.
开门
Open those doors!
快点
Coming through.
我们爱你  约翰
We love you, John!
上帝保佑你  我也会这么做的
God bless you, John! I'd do the same thing!
加油  约翰
Go, John!
心脏
Heart.
谢谢
Thank you.
长剪
Metzenbaums.
他很衰弱
He's hypostenic.
等等
Wait a second.
为我戴上它们吧  可以吗?
Put these on for, would you do that?
慢慢来
Take your time.
拉起来
Life it.
好
All right.
完成了
Done.
升高血压
Pressure up.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
成功了
It worked!
成功了  约翰  成功了
It worked, John! It worked!
又是一桩案例...
The other big story...
约翰被控绑架与企图谋杀
John Q goes on trial today for kidnapping and attempted murder charges.
全因为HMO拒绝给付
All because an HMO denied coverage
他儿子的心脏移植手术
For his son's heart transplant.
未来更糟  HMO会拒绝承保
It'll be more expensive for you, HMO's, to deny coverage when people need it.
还有四千万美国人没有保险
There are still 40 million Americans who are uninsured.
今晚  约翰·亚契的审判继续着
Tonight, as the trial continues, John Quincy Archibald:
他是坏蛋还是好父亲?
Vigilante or heroic father?
你来决定
You decide.
告垮他们  好让他们知道...
Sue the pants off them for millions of dollars to let them know...
我们早知道这个健保系统很烂
We've know for years that this is a crappy health care system.
政府根本不在乎我们
The government don't care about us.
我想约翰用的是信心健保计划
I guess John Q was using one of those faith-bassed health care plans.
你只能祈祷  政府才不管你
That's where you just pray, and the government does nothing.
重点是我们的敌人
The point is that the enemy
根本就是我们自己
That we're trying to identify is us.
那才是重点
That's the point.
我们才是终结健保系统的人
We are the ones who shot down national health care.
（三个月后）
我们不希望税金提高
We are the ones who don't want our taxes raised.
你们必须仔细审视这个问题
You have to look in the mirror for this problem.
退后  拜托  退后
Back up. Come on, back up.
就回答一个问题吧
Just one question, please!
退后
Back up.
让开  走吧
Out of the way. Let's go.
你现在有何感觉  约翰?
How are you feeling right now, John?
陪审团是否已达成判决?
Has the jury reached a verdict?
是的  庭上
We have, Your Honor.
第一项罪名  蓄意谋杀...
As to count one: Attempted murder...
我们认为被告  约翰·亚契...
we find the defendant, John Quincy Archibald...
无罪
not quilty.
请安静
Quiet, please.
第二项罪名
On count two:
非法持械攻击...
Armed criminal action...
无罪
not quilty.
安静
Quiet!
最后一项罪名
On the final count:
绑架并囚禁毕朱莉...
The kidnapping and false imprisonment of Julie Byrd...
柯麦斯  冈萝莎...
Max Conlan, Rosa Gonzalez...
艾伦克莱医生...
Dr. Ellen Klein...
马莱斯  麦史提...
Lester Matthews, Steve Maguire...
施蜜丽和施史提...
Miriam and Steve Smith...
雷透纳医生...
Dr. Raymond Turner...
昆米区  欧黛比...
Mitch Quigley, Debby Utley...
我们认为被告...
we find the defendant...
有罪
guilty.
请安静
Quiet, please.
一周后宣判
Sentencing will be one week from today.
全体起立
All rise.
我们会得到什么处罚?
So, what are we looking at?
他会坐一阵子牢
Well, he's going to do some time.
法官不会判他超过三到五年
The judge is not going to give him more than three to five,
我会设法降到两年
I'll try for two.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你还好吧  大强棒?
You all right, slugger?
很好
Yeah.
好好照顾你妈
Take good care of your mother, okay?
你现在是家里唯一的男人了
You're the man of the house now.
有问题  吉米和吉娜会帮你
Any problems, Jimmy and Gina will be here for you too.
好
Okay.
我以你为荣
I'm so proud of you.
让他们瞧瞧你的厉害
Give them frigging hell, Johnny.
你什么都别担心了
Don't worry about nothing.
爸?
Hey, Dad?
再见
Goodbye.
这不是再见  儿子
It's not goodbye, son.
回头见
See you later.
约翰
Hey, John!
保重  老兄
Take care, man.
你是我的英雄
You're my hero.
爸
Dad!
谢谢你
Thank you.